<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Southwest on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/southwest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Southwest on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/southwest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nirrith</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/nirrith/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/nirrith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nirriti-the-hindu-goddess-of-destruction-and-misfortune&#34;&gt;Nirriti: The Hindu Goddess of Destruction and Misfortune&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nirriti is a complex and often misunderstood Hindu goddess primarily associated with destruction, misfortune, calamity, and chaos. Unlike many other deities who embody both positive and negative aspects, Nirriti is largely perceived as a personification of negativity and the antithesis of order and auspiciousness. While not actively worshipped in the same way as deities like Lakshmi or Shiva, understanding Nirriti is crucial for comprehending the multifaceted nature of the Hindu pantheon and the cyclical nature of existence, including the acknowledgement of darkness and negativity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nirrta</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/nirrta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/nirrta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nirṛti-the-hindu-goddess-of-misfortune-and-dissolution&#34;&gt;Nirṛti: The Hindu Goddess of Misfortune and Dissolution&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nirṛti, also spelled Nirriti, is a Hindu goddess embodying misfortune, calamity, and destruction. Often associated with death and decay, she represents the absence of ṛta (cosmic order) and the forces that unravel prosperity and well-being. While not as prominently worshipped as some other deities in the Hindu pantheon, Nirṛti holds a significant place as a potent force within the cyclical nature of existence, highlighting the inevitable presence of negativity and the need to acknowledge and navigate life&amp;rsquo;s adversities. She embodies the entropy that balances creation and preservation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
