<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Durga on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/durga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Durga on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/durga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jagaddhatri</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/jagaddhatri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/jagaddhatri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jagaddhatri-sustainer-of-the-world&#34;&gt;Jagaddhatri: Sustainer of the World&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jagaddhatri (IAST: Jagaddhātrī; Devanagari: जगद्धात्री) is a revered Hindu goddess, particularly prominent in the states of West Bengal, Odisha, and Assam in India. She is considered a form of Durga, representing the power that upholds and sustains the universe. Unlike Durga&amp;rsquo;s fierce and warrior-like depictions, Jagaddhatri embodies a calmer, more regal form, symbolizing the power of balance and cosmic order. Her key attributes include being seated on a lion, wielding weapons, and holding a conch, discus, arrow, and bow. She is worshipped for her role in maintaining equilibrium and protecting the world from chaos. Her significance lies in her representation of the ultimate power that controls the universe and guides devotees towards spiritual liberation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mahishasura Mardini</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/mahishasura-mardini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/mahishasura-mardini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mahishasura-mardini-the-slayer-of-the-buffalo-demon&#34;&gt;Mahishasura Mardini: The Slayer of the Buffalo Demon&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mahishasura Mardini, often simply referred to as Durga, is a powerful and revered deity in Hinduism, particularly within the Shaktism tradition. She is primarily known as the slayer of the buffalo-demon Mahishasura, embodying the triumph of good over evil, and divine feminine power (Shakti). Iconographically, she is depicted as a warrior goddess riding a lion or tiger, wielding an array of weapons and engaging in combat with the demon Mahishasura. Her significance lies in her ability to restore cosmic balance, protect devotees, and represent the potential for overcoming adversity within oneself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shantadurga</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/shantadurga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/shantadurga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;shantadurga-the-peaceful-form-of-durga&#34;&gt;Shantadurga: The Peaceful Form of Durga&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shantadurga, also known as Santeri, is a prominent Hindu goddess primarily worshipped in Goa, India. She represents a unique synthesis of power (Shakti) and peace (Shanti), embodying a form of Durga who pacifies conflict and restores harmony. Unlike the often fierce and warrior-like depictions of Durga in other regions, Shantadurga is typically represented in a serene and benevolent form, often associated with motherhood and protection. She is revered as a powerful yet compassionate deity, a protector of her devotees and a symbol of reconciliation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vana Durga</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vana-durga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vana-durga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vana-durga-the-forest-goddess-of-protection-and-power&#34;&gt;Vana Durga: The Forest Goddess of Protection and Power&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vana Durga, meaning &amp;ldquo;Durga of the Forest,&amp;rdquo; is a specific form of the Hindu Goddess Durga primarily worshipped in wilderness settings, particularly forests and remote shrines. She represents the raw, untamed power of nature, acting as a guardian of the forest and its inhabitants. While sharing the fundamental attributes of Durga, she embodies a more primal and immediate connection to the natural world. Her worship emphasizes her role as a protector against dangers, both physical and spiritual, encountered in the wild. Key attributes include her fierce appearance, her connection to nature, and her role as a powerful protector. Iconographically, she is often depicted holding weapons and riding a lion or other animal associated with the forest. Vana Durga holds significant importance in Hinduism, particularly within Shaktism, as a manifestation of the divine feminine power (Shakti) residing within the natural world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
