<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dras on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/categories/dras/</link><description>Recent content in Dras on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:57:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/categories/dras/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dras War Memorial: A Tribute to Kargil Heroes</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/jammu--kashmir/dras-war-memorial-a-tribute-to-kargil-heroes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/jammu--kashmir/dras-war-memorial-a-tribute-to-kargil-heroes/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dras War Memorial, also known as the Kargil War Memorial, stands as a poignant and enduring tribute to the bravery and sacrifice of Indian soldiers who fought valiantly during the Kargil War of 1999. Located in Dras, a strategically important town in the Kargil district of Ladakh, Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir, the memorial sits at a breathtaking altitude, offering stunning views of the surrounding Himalayan terrain and the very peaks where the intense battles were fought. This somber yet inspiring monument serves as a constant reminder of the valor, resilience, and ultimate sacrifice made by the Indian Armed Forces. It’s situated approximately 55 km west of Kargil town, and en route to the town of Leh. What makes the Dras War Memorial unique is not just its tribute to fallen soldiers but also its location, on the very battleground where history was made, adding a layer of profound significance.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Exploring the Enchanting Beauty of Dras</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/jammu--kashmir/exploring-the-enchanting-beauty-of-dras/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/jammu--kashmir/exploring-the-enchanting-beauty-of-dras/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dras, often dubbed the &amp;ldquo;Gateway to Ladakh,&amp;rdquo; is a remote and captivating town situated in the Kargil district of Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir, India. Nestled at an average elevation of approximately 10,760 feet (3,280 meters), Dras holds the distinction of being the second coldest inhabited place on Earth. It lies approximately 60 km west of Kargil and serves as a crucial transit point on the Srinagar-Leh highway (NH1), making it a vital stop for travelers exploring Ladakh. Dras&amp;rsquo;s dramatic landscapes, raw beauty, and harsh climate offer a unique and unforgettable travel experience, a world away from the more populated and developed regions. Its unique combination of high-altitude terrain, dramatic valleys, and a resilient local population make Dras an intriguing destination.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>