<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Six-Faced on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/six-faced/</link><description>Recent content in Six-Faced on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:55:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/six-faced/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kartikeya</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/kartikeya/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/kartikeya/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="kartikeya-the-god-of-war-and-divine-commander"&gt;Kartikeya: The God of War and Divine Commander&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kartikeya, also widely known as Murugan, Skanda, Subramanya, and several other names, is a prominent Hindu deity revered primarily as the god of war and commander-in-chief of the celestial army. He is the son of Shiva and Parvati, and a significant figure in Hindu mythology, particularly in South India, Sri Lanka, and Southeast Asia. Kartikeya is typically depicted as a youthful warrior, often riding a peacock (his vahana or vehicle), wielding a spear (vel), and embodying courage, strength, and wisdom. He is venerated as a protector, a guide, and an embodiment of divine power. His significance in Hinduism extends beyond his role as a warrior; he is seen as a symbol of overcoming obstacles, achieving self-realization, and upholding dharma (righteousness).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Skanda</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/skanda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/skanda/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="skanda-the-hindu-god-of-war-and-victory"&gt;Skanda: The Hindu God of War and Victory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skanda, also widely recognized as Kartikeya, Murugan, Subramanya, and Shanmukha, is a prominent Hindu deity, primarily revered as the god of war and victory. He is the son of Shiva and Parvati, and the brother of Ganesha. Skanda embodies courage, leadership, and righteous battle. His iconography frequently depicts him as a youthful, handsome warrior, riding a peacock and wielding a spear (Vel). He is a significant deity across India and beyond, particularly in South India, where he is known as Murugan and celebrated with fervent devotion. Skanda&amp;rsquo;s presence symbolizes the power of righteousness overcoming evil and serves as an inspiration for strength and valor in the face of adversity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>