<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Folk Songs on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/folk-songs/</link><description>Recent content in Folk Songs on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:55:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/folk-songs/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jitiya</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/jitiya/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/jitiya/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="jitiya-a-mothers-unwavering-love--the-thread-of-tradition"&gt;Jitiya: A Mother&amp;rsquo;s Unwavering Love &amp;amp; the Thread of Tradition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever encountered a love so profound, so deeply rooted, that it manifested as an unwavering fast, a silent prayer woven with unwavering devotion? Welcome to Jitiya, a vibrant and emotionally charged festival celebrated primarily in Bihar, Jharkhand, and parts of Nepal. It’s a testament to the powerful bond between a mother and her child, a celebration of fertility, protection, and the enduring strength of maternal love. For someone unfamiliar with the tapestry of Indian festivals, Jitiya might seem austere with its focus on fasting. But delve deeper, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find a rich tapestry of traditions, folklore, and an unbreakable thread connecting generations of women. I remember growing up watching my own mother observe this fast. The determination etched on her face, the quiet prayers whispered under her breath – it left an indelible impression on me, a testament to a mother’s relentless dedication. Jitiya is more than just a festival; it’s a living embodiment of a mother’s love, passed down through generations like a cherished heirloom. Prepare to be moved by the dedication, the vibrant colors, and the poignant stories that make Jitiya a truly unforgettable celebration.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lohri</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/lohri/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/lohri/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="lohri-fireside-stories-sweet-treats-and-welcoming-the-sun"&gt;Lohri: Fireside Stories, Sweet Treats, and Welcoming the Sun&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine crackling bonfires under a star-studded sky, the aroma of roasting peanuts mingling with the rhythmic beat of the dhol, and laughter echoing through the crisp winter air. This is Lohri, a vibrant North Indian festival that paints the landscape with warmth and camaraderie. More than just a celebration, Lohri is a heartfelt expression of gratitude for the winter harvest, a joyous welcoming of longer days, and a powerful reminder of the importance of community and family. For me, growing up in Punjab, Lohri was always a highlight of the year, a time to shed the winter blues and embrace the promise of spring. Even though I now live far away, the memories of Lohri bonfires and shared moments with loved ones still feel incredibly vivid. Whether you’re already familiar with this festive occasion or simply curious to learn more, come join me as we delve into the heart of Lohri, uncovering its rich history, unique traditions, and the joyous spirit that makes it so special. From the ancient mythology to the modern-day celebrations, get ready to be transported to the heart of a truly magical cultural experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tusu Parab</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/tusu-parab/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/tusu-parab/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tusu-parab-where-the-harvest-meets-the-heart-in-rural-india"&gt;Tusu Parab: Where the Harvest Meets the Heart in Rural India&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a vibrant tapestry of colors, the rhythmic beat of drums echoing through the fields, and the scent of freshly harvested rice mingling with the sweet aroma of homemade sweets. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just a scene from a storybook; it&amp;rsquo;s the essence of Tusu Parab, a captivating folk festival celebrated during Makar Sankranti in parts of West Bengal, Jharkhand, and Odisha, predominantly by the tribal communities. Tusu Parab is more than just a celebration; it&amp;rsquo;s a heartfelt expression of gratitude for the bountiful harvest, a vibrant display of cultural heritage, and a strengthening of community bonds.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>