<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Feminine Power on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/feminine-power/</link><description>Recent content in Feminine Power on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:55:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/feminine-power/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Draupadi</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/draupadi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/draupadi/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="draupadi-a-hindu-goddess-and-symbol-of-dharma"&gt;Draupadi: A Hindu Goddess and Symbol of Dharma&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** Introduction**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Draupadi, also known as Krishnaa, Panchali, and Yajnaseni, is a prominent figure in Hindu mythology, primarily recognized as the wife of the five Pandava brothers in the epic Mahabharata. While her role is central to the narrative&amp;rsquo;s unfolding and its exploration of dharma, justice, and karma, Draupadi is also worshipped as a goddess in various parts of India, particularly in Tamil Nadu and parts of Karnataka. She represents strength, resilience, and unwavering adherence to dharma in the face of adversity. Her significance lies not only in her narrative within the Mahabharata but also in her ongoing veneration as a powerful female deity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Durga</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/durga/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/durga/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="durga-the-invincible-goddess-of-power-and-protection"&gt;Durga: The Invincible Goddess of Power and Protection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Durga, meaning &amp;ldquo;the invincible&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;the inaccessible,&amp;rdquo; is a major deity in Hinduism, revered primarily as the warrior goddess who combats evil forces and restores dharma (righteousness). She is considered a fierce and powerful form of Parvati, the consort of Shiva, and embodies strength, motherhood, destruction, and protection. Durga’s iconography often depicts her as a multi-armed goddess riding a lion or tiger, wielding a variety of weapons to symbolize her ability to overcome any obstacle. Her worship is widespread, particularly during the festival of Durga Puja, and she is seen as a symbol of female power (Shakti) and the triumph of good over evil. In Hinduism, Durga&amp;rsquo;s significance lies in her role as the ultimate protector, capable of safeguarding devotees from all forms of adversity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Yogini</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/yogini/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/yogini/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="yogini-female-powers-and-tantric-practices-in-hinduism"&gt;Yogini: Female Powers and Tantric Practices in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Yoginis are a group of powerful female entities within Hinduism, often considered to be goddesses embodying supernatural abilities and associated with Tantric practices. They are viewed as both benevolent and potentially fierce, wielders of occult powers (siddhis), and integral to certain esoteric Hindu traditions, particularly Shaktism (the worship of the Divine Feminine). While not a single deity, the Yoginis are typically worshipped as a group, either as a collective of 64 or 81 entities, or in smaller groups. Their worship is central to Yogini temples, which are often circular in design, representing the cyclical nature of time and the cosmos. The Yoginis hold a significant place in the Tantric landscape, symbolizing the activation of inner energies and the attainment of spiritual liberation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>