<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Agriculture on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/agriculture/</link><description>Recent content in Agriculture on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:55:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/agriculture/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bhumiya</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/bhumiya/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/bhumiya/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="bhumiya-the-earth-deity-in-hinduism"&gt;Bhumiya: The Earth Deity in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bhumiya, also known as Bhumi Devi or simply Bhumi, is the Hindu goddess representing the Earth. As a personification of the terrestrial sphere, she is considered a foundational deity, revered for her role in providing sustenance and fertility. Bhumiya is an integral part of the Hindu cosmological framework, often regarded as the consort of Vishnu and a powerful symbol of abundance, patience, and the nurturing aspects of the divine feminine. Her worship is particularly prominent in agricultural communities, where her blessings are sought for bountiful harvests and the well-being of the land.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bihu</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/bihu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/bihu/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="bihu-a-trio-of-celebrations-weaving-assams-soul-with-the-seasons"&gt;Bihu: A Trio of Celebrations Weaving Assam&amp;rsquo;s Soul with the Seasons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a land bathed in the golden glow of harvest, where the air vibrates with the rhythmic beats of the &lt;em&gt;dhol&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;pepa&lt;/em&gt;, and the scent of &lt;em&gt;pitha&lt;/em&gt; (rice cakes) fills every home. Welcome to Assam, where life revolves around the mighty Brahmaputra river and the vibrant festival of Bihu! Bihu isn&amp;rsquo;t just one celebration; it&amp;rsquo;s a trio of festivals marking crucial points in the agricultural cycle, each with its unique flavor and significance. As an Indian, I can tell you Bihu isn&amp;rsquo;t just a festival; it&amp;rsquo;s a feeling, a connection to our roots, and a celebration of life itself. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re deeply familiar with Indian culture or just starting to explore its richness, get ready to be captivated by the sights, sounds, and spirit of Bihu. Prepare to be swept away by a cultural tapestry woven with tradition, community, and the unwavering rhythm of nature. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just about knowing &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; Bihu is; it&amp;rsquo;s about understanding &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; it&amp;rsquo;s so deeply cherished by the people of Assam, both at home and around the world. So, come, let’s delve into the heart of Assam and discover the magic of Bihu!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pola</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/pola/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/pola/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="pola-where-maharashtra-celebrates-the-mighty-bull--bountiful-harvest"&gt;Pola: Where Maharashtra Celebrates the Mighty Bull &amp;amp; Bountiful Harvest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever stopped to consider the role of animals in shaping our lives, particularly in agriculture? In the heart of Maharashtra, and spilling over into parts of Madhya Pradesh, a vibrant and deeply meaningful festival called Pola unfolds each year, a powerful ode to the bulls that tirelessly till the land and contribute to the prosperity of the harvest. Pola isn&amp;rsquo;t just a festival; it&amp;rsquo;s a heartfelt &amp;ldquo;thank you&amp;rdquo; whispered on the wind, a burst of color and joy expressing gratitude for these essential partners in farming. As someone who grew up witnessing this spectacle every year, I can tell you it&amp;rsquo;s an experience that stays with you – the sounds of bells, the vibrant colors, and the tangible feeling of community swirling in the air. For those unfamiliar with Indian agrarian traditions, Pola offers a unique glimpse into the deep connection between humans, animals, and the earth. So, join me as we delve into the sights, sounds, and soul of this beautiful celebration!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>