<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Munnar on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/categories/munnar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Munnar on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/categories/munnar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Explore Biodiversity at Eravikulam National Park</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/kerala/explore-biodiversity-at-eravikulam-national-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/kerala/explore-biodiversity-at-eravikulam-national-park/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Munnar, a breathtaking hill station nestled in the Western Ghats mountain range of Kerala, India, is a destination synonymous with verdant tea plantations, rolling hills, and crisp mountain air. Situated in the Idukki district, Munnar lies at an elevation of approximately 1,700 meters (5,600 feet) above sea level, offering panoramic views and a cool climate that sets it apart from the tropical lowlands. Its proximity to other popular Kerala destinations like Kochi and Thekkady makes it an accessible yet secluded retreat. Munnar&amp;rsquo;s unique allure stems from its extensive tea estates, the pristine beauty of its shola forests, and its cultural heritage shaped by the history of tea cultivation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vaishno Devi Temple: A Pilgrimage to Goddess Vaishno Devi</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/jammu--kashmir/vaishno-devi-temple-a-pilgrimage-to-goddess-vaishno-devi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/jammu--kashmir/vaishno-devi-temple-a-pilgrimage-to-goddess-vaishno-devi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vaishno Devi Temple in Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir, often referred to as the &amp;ldquo;holy cave shrine,&amp;rdquo; is a revered pilgrimage site dedicated to the Hindu goddess Vaishnavi. Contrary to a possible misinterpretation of location, this article focuses on the widely known Vaishno Devi shrine located in the Trikuta Mountains, near Katra, in the Jammu region of Jammu &amp;amp; Kashmir. This sacred destination is a cornerstone of faith for millions of devotees worldwide. Situated at an elevation of approximately 5,200 feet (1,585 meters) above sea level, the temple offers breathtaking views of the surrounding valleys and mountains. It’s a place where spirituality and natural beauty converge, drawing pilgrims and tourists alike. The trek to the shrine, often undertaken on foot, is a significant part of the spiritual journey. It is unique because it combines arduous physical effort, a profound sense of devotion, and a deep connection to the divine. The temple’s history is interwoven with tales of the goddess’s divine presence, offering a deeply moving experience for its visitors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
