<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Star on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/star/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Star on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/star/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Arundhati</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/arundhati/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/arundhati/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;arundhati-embodiment-of-virtue-and-constancy&#34;&gt;Arundhati: Embodiment of Virtue and Constancy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;** Introduction**&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arundhati is a revered figure in Hinduism, primarily recognized as the wife of the esteemed sage Vashishta. She is not considered a goddess in the traditional sense, but rather a woman of exceptional virtue, devotion, and unwavering fidelity. She is intrinsically linked to the Saptarishi, the seven great sages, and is often identified with the morning star and the Alcor star, a faint companion star to Mizar in the constellation Ursa Major (the Big Dipper). Arundhati serves as an exemplar of marital devotion, chastity, and asceticism, making her a significant figure in Hindu traditions relating to marriage, family, and spiritual life. While not receiving widespread temple worship, her veneration lies in the symbolic representation of ideal womanhood and the invocation of her name in marriage rituals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rohini Nakshatram</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/rohini-nakshatram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/rohini-nakshatram/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;rohini-nakshatram-star-goddess-and-consort-of-chandra&#34;&gt;Rohini Nakshatram: Star Goddess and Consort of Chandra&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rohini Nakshatram is a significant figure in Hindu astrology and mythology. She is revered as a star goddess and is most prominently known as the favorite consort of Chandra, the moon god. Rohini is associated with beauty, fertility, and prosperity, and her influence is considered potent in shaping destinies based on the lunar mansion (Nakshatra) in which she resides. While not a primary deity in the same vein as Vishnu or Shiva, her influence is deeply interwoven into the fabric of astrological and religious practices within Hinduism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tara</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/tara/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/tara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tara-the-goddess-of-protection-and-compassion-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Tara: The Goddess of Protection and Compassion in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tara, also known as Tārā (तारा), is a significant Hindu goddess revered primarily for her roles in protection, guidance, and compassion. Though more prominently featured in Vajrayana Buddhism, Tara also holds a respected position in Hinduism, particularly within Shaktism. She is often invoked for overcoming obstacles, granting wishes, and leading devotees towards enlightenment.  Tara&amp;rsquo;s iconography typically depicts her as a compassionate figure, embodying nurturing and supportive qualities. Her significance in Hinduism, although lesser known than some other goddesses, stems from her powerful connection to wisdom, deliverance, and the alleviation of suffering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zorya</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/zorya/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/zorya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;zorya-the-elusive-dawn-goddess-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Zorya: The Elusive Dawn Goddess in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;** Introduction**&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The name &amp;ldquo;Zorya,&amp;rdquo; designating deities representing the morning and evening stars, is primarily associated with Slavic mythology. &lt;em&gt;There is no recognized deity called Zorya within mainstream Hindu traditions, texts, or pantheon&lt;/em&gt;. The concept of morning and evening stars is represented, but not by a single named deity directly corresponding to the Slavic Zorya. This article will explore how the &lt;em&gt;concept&lt;/em&gt; of dawn and dusk, and the celestial bodies associated with them, are represented in Hinduism through various deities and concepts. We will examine how deities like Ushas (dawn) and Sandhya (twilight) embody similar themes and roles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
