<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Judgment on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/judgment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Judgment on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/judgment/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chitragupta</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/chitragupta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/chitragupta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chitragupta-the-divine-accountant-of-karma&#34;&gt;Chitragupta: The Divine Accountant of Karma&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chitragupta, a prominent deity in Hinduism, is revered as the keeper of records for all human actions. His primary function is to meticulously document the good and bad deeds (karma) of every individual and, after death, determine their fate in the afterlife. He is often depicted as a divine scribe, holding a pen, inkpot, and ledger, symbolizing his role in recording and assessing the karmic consequences of human lives. Chitragupta&amp;rsquo;s significance lies in his association with dharma (righteousness), karma (action), and moksha (liberation), highlighting the Hindu belief in the law of cause and effect and the importance of living a virtuous life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yama</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/yama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/yama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;yama-the-lord-of-death-and-justice-in-hindu-cosmology&#34;&gt;Yama: The Lord of Death and Justice in Hindu Cosmology&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yama, also known as Yamaraja, is the Hindu god of death, justice, and dharma. He holds a prominent and multifaceted role in Hindu cosmology, serving as the judge of the departed souls and the guardian of the southern direction (Dakshina). While often associated with fear and the end of life, Yama&amp;rsquo;s position is crucial for maintaining cosmic order and upholding the principles of karma and dharma. He ensures that every soul receives its due consequences based on its actions in life, ultimately guiding them towards the cycle of rebirth and the possibility of moksha (liberation).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
