<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ambedkar on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/ambedkar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ambedkar on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/ambedkar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dhammachakra Pravartan Day</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/dhammachakra-pravartan-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/dhammachakra-pravartan-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-day-of-awakening-celebrating-dhammachakra-pravartan-day-and-the-embrace-of-buddhism-in-india&#34;&gt;A Day of Awakening: Celebrating Dhammachakra Pravartan Day and the Embrace of Buddhism in India&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a sea of people, draped in white, their faces radiating peace and purpose. Chants of &amp;ldquo;Buddham Sharanam Gacchami&amp;rdquo; (I go to the Buddha for refuge) fill the air, creating an atmosphere of profound serenity and hope. This is a glimpse into Dhammachakra Pravartan Day, a pivotal event in modern Indian history and a celebration of Dr. B.R. Ambedkar&amp;rsquo;s historic conversion to Buddhism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manusmriti Dahan Din</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/manusmriti-dahan-din/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/manusmriti-dahan-din/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;burning-the-chains-understanding-manusmriti-dahan-din--a-festival-of-equality&#34;&gt;Burning the Chains: Understanding Manusmriti Dahan Din – A Festival of Equality&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard of a festival that commemorates the burning of a book? In India, Manusmriti Dahan Din, observed primarily by Dalit communities, isn&amp;rsquo;t just about destruction; it&amp;rsquo;s about a powerful act of defiance and a fervent cry for equality. It’s a day to remember and celebrate Dr. B.R. Ambedkar, the architect of the Indian Constitution and a champion of social justice, and his symbolic burning of the Manusmriti, an ancient Hindu text, in 1927. This act wasn’t about rejecting religion but about rejecting a system of rigid social stratification that for centuries had relegated a large segment of the population to the margins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
