<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strength on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/strength/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Strength on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/strength/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hanuman</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/hanuman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/hanuman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hanuman-the-embodiment-of-devotion-and-strength&#34;&gt;Hanuman: The Embodiment of Devotion and Strength&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hanuman, also known as Anjaneya, is one of the most beloved and revered deities in Hinduism. He is celebrated for his unparalleled devotion to Lord Rama, his extraordinary strength, unwavering courage, and selfless service. Often depicted as a monkey-faced humanoid, Hanuman embodies the ideals of &lt;em&gt;bhakti&lt;/em&gt; (devotion), &lt;em&gt;shakti&lt;/em&gt; (power), and &lt;em&gt;buddhi&lt;/em&gt; (wisdom). His iconography typically portrays him as a muscular figure, often carrying the &lt;em&gt;gada&lt;/em&gt; (mace), a symbol of his might. Hanuman holds a prominent position in the Hindu pantheon, particularly within the Vaishnava tradition, and is venerated as a protector, a source of strength, and a symbol of unwavering faith.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hanuman Jayanti</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/hanuman-jayanti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/hanuman-jayanti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hanuman-jayanti-a-celebration-of-strength-devotion-and-the-monkey-god&#34;&gt;Hanuman Jayanti: A Celebration of Strength, Devotion, and the Monkey God&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a day filled with the rhythmic chanting of mantras, the aroma of freshly baked sweets, and the vibrant colors of ochre and vermillion adorning every temple. This is Hanuman Jayanti, a day dedicated to celebrating the birth of Lord Hanuman, a revered deity in Hinduism known for his unparalleled devotion, unwavering strength, and boundless perseverance. It’s more than just a birthday; it’s a powerful reminder of the qualities we should all strive for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
