<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Love on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/love/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Love on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/love/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Parvati</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/parvati/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/parvati/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;parvati-the-goddess-of-love-devotion-and-divine-power&#34;&gt;Parvati: The Goddess of Love, Devotion, and Divine Power&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Parvati, the Hindu goddess of love, fertility, devotion, and divine strength, is widely revered as the consort of Lord Shiva and the mother of Ganesha and Kartikeya (Skanda). She embodies the feminine principle (Shakti) and is considered the complete manifestation of Adi Shakti, the primordial cosmic energy. Iconographically, Parvati is often depicted as a beautiful woman with a benevolent expression, adorned with traditional Indian jewelry and clothing. She is a central figure in the Hindu pantheon, symbolizing marital harmony, motherhood, and the power of feminine energy in achieving spiritual liberation. Parvati&amp;rsquo;s significance lies not only in her role as Shiva&amp;rsquo;s consort but also in her independent power and the myriad forms she assumes to protect devotees and uphold dharma.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rati</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/rati/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/rati/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;rati-the-hindu-goddess-of-love-and-desire&#34;&gt;Rati: The Hindu Goddess of Love and Desire&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rati is the Hindu goddess of love, passion, carnal desire, and sexual pleasure. She is the consort of Kama, the god of love. Rati is integral to understanding the Hindu concept of &lt;em&gt;kama&lt;/em&gt;, one of the four &lt;em&gt;purusharthas&lt;/em&gt; (aims of human life), representing pleasure, enjoyment, and aesthetic fulfillment. Often depicted as a beautiful and alluring young woman, Rati embodies the captivating and irresistible nature of desire. While not as widely worshipped as some other major Hindu goddesses, her influence is felt in various aspects of Indian culture, from literature and art to festivals and rituals focused on love and marital bliss.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
