<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shringeri on Beautiful India</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/shringeri/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shringeri on Beautiful India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/shringeri/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shringeri Sharada Peetham: A Sacred Shrine in Karnataka</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/karnataka/shringeri-sharada-peetham-a-sacred-shrine-in-karnataka/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/karnataka/shringeri-sharada-peetham-a-sacred-shrine-in-karnataka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shringeri Sharada Peetham, nestled in the heart of the Western Ghats in Karnataka, is a revered Hindu monastery and the first of the four Mathas (monasteries) established by the great philosopher and theologian, Adi Shankaracharya. Located on the banks of the Tunga River in the Chikmagalur district, at an elevation of approximately 680 meters (2230 feet) above sea level, Shringeri is a place of immense spiritual significance. It offers a serene escape from the bustling city life, characterized by lush greenery, tranquil surroundings, and a rich cultural heritage. The town’s close proximity to popular destinations like Chikmagalur and Kudremukh makes it a convenient stopover for tourists exploring the region. Shringeri is unique due to its unbroken lineage of Acharyas (spiritual heads) since its founding, its commitment to the Advaita Vedanta philosophy, and its reputation as a center for learning and spiritual contemplation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
