<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Non-Violence on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/non-violence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Non-Violence on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/non-violence/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gandhi Jayanti</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/gandhi-jayanti/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/gandhi-jayanti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-than-just-a-holiday-discovering-the-soul-of-gandhi-jayanti&#34;&gt;More Than Just a Holiday: Discovering the Soul of Gandhi Jayanti&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a day filled with quiet reflection, the gentle hum of spinning wheels, and the resonant echoes of prayer. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just another day off; it&amp;rsquo;s Gandhi Jayanti, a day deeply etched in the Indian psyche. For those unfamiliar with Indian culture, it might seem like just another national holiday. But trust me, it&amp;rsquo;s so much more. It&amp;rsquo;s a powerful reminder of the values that shaped a nation and continue to resonate across the globe – peace, truth, non-violence, and simple living.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mahavir Janma Kalyanak</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/mahavir-janma-kalyanak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/mahavir-janma-kalyanak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mahavir-janma-kalyanak-celebrating-the-awakened-one-and-a-life-of-ahimsa&#34;&gt;Mahavir Janma Kalyanak: Celebrating the Awakened One and a Life of Ahimsa&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a day filled with vibrant processions, the gentle chants of prayers, and the palpable sense of peace emanating from ancient temples. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just any day; it&amp;rsquo;s Mahavir Janma Kalyanak, the most significant festival for Jains worldwide, celebrating the birth of Lord Mahavira, the 24th Tirthankara. As someone deeply fascinated by the diversity of Indian culture, I find this festival particularly inspiring because it embodies principles of non-violence, compassion, and self-discipline – values that resonate deeply in today&amp;rsquo;s world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paryushan</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/paryushan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/paryushan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;paryushan-unveiling-the-soul-of-jainism-through-forgiveness-and-reflection&#34;&gt;Paryushan: Unveiling the Soul of Jainism Through Forgiveness and Reflection&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever felt the urge to press the reset button on your life? To take a step back from the daily grind, confront your missteps, and emerge with a renewed sense of purpose and compassion? For Jains around the world, Paryushan is that opportunity – a profound period of introspection, repentance, and spiritual cleansing that culminates in a collective expression of forgiveness. More than just a religious observance, Paryushan is a vibrant tapestry of ancient traditions, philosophical depth, and unwavering commitment to non-violence. It&amp;rsquo;s a chance to reconnect with your inner self and strengthen the bonds of community through shared reflection and ethical living.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
