<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Night on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/night/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Night on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/night/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ratri</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/ratri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/ratri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ratri-the-hindu-goddess-of-night&#34;&gt;Ratri: The Hindu Goddess of Night&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ratri, often translated as &amp;ldquo;Night,&amp;rdquo; is a significant Hindu goddess embodying the darkness, mystery, and tranquility of the night. She is primarily recognized as the personification of night itself, representing the transition from day to night and the rest and rejuvenation that darkness brings. While not as widely worshipped as some other Hindu deities like Lakshmi or Saraswati, Ratri holds a crucial position in Vedic thought and represents a fundamental aspect of the cosmos. She is often depicted as a benevolent protectress who shields beings from danger and provides solace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yamini</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/yamini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/yamini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;yamini-goddess-of-night-and-darkness-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Yamini: Goddess of Night and Darkness in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;** Introduction**&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yamini, in Hindu tradition, is a goddess who embodies the essence of night and darkness. Often viewed as a powerful and mysterious figure, she represents the stillness, introspection, and transformative potential associated with the night. While not as widely worshipped as some of the major Hindu deities, Yamini holds a significant position as a personification of the natural cycle and a symbol of the unseen forces that govern the world. She is often seen as a counterpart to deities representing light and day, completing the cosmic balance. Her iconography and significance vary across different Hindu texts and traditions, but she consistently embodies the profound aspects of the night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
