<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parade on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/parade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Parade on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/parade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Carnival</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/carnival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/carnival/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;viva-carnival-goas-electrifying-farewell-to-restraint-before-lent&#34;&gt;Viva Carnival! Goa&amp;rsquo;s Electrifying Farewell to Restraint Before Lent&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever felt the urge to throw all caution to the wind, embrace pure joy, and dance until your feet ache? In Goa, India, that feeling isn’t just an urge – it&amp;rsquo;s a tradition! For four glorious days before Lent, the smallest state in India erupts in a riot of color, music, and merriment, celebrating Carnival, or &amp;ldquo;Intruz&amp;rdquo; as it&amp;rsquo;s locally known. Forget your everyday worries; this is a time for pure, unadulterated fun, a final burst of revelry before a period of reflection and fasting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indian Republic Day</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/indian-republic-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/indian-republic-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-nation-united-celebrating-indias-republic-day-with-pride-and-patriotism&#34;&gt;A Nation United: Celebrating India&amp;rsquo;s Republic Day with Pride and Patriotism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a tapestry woven with threads of vibrant saffron, pristine white, and tranquil green, a symphony of marching boots echoing down Rajpath, and the roar of fighter jets painting the sky with tricolor smoke. This is India’s Republic Day, a spectacle that fills the heart with pride and commemorates a pivotal moment in the nation&amp;rsquo;s journey – the day India adopted its own Constitution and truly became a sovereign, secular, and democratic republic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
