<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trimurti on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/trimurti/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Trimurti on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/trimurti/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brahma</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/brahma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/brahma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;brahma-the-creator-god-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Brahma: The Creator God in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brahma is the Hindu god of creation and one of the Trimurti, the divine triad that includes Vishnu (the preserver) and Shiva (the destroyer). Though a pivotal figure in Hindu cosmology, Brahma is not as widely worshipped as Vishnu and Shiva. He is often depicted with four faces, four arms, and is associated with knowledge and the Vedas. His significance lies in his role as the originator of the universe and all living beings, a fundamental aspect of the Hindu worldview.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shiva</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/shiva/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/shiva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;shiva-the-destroyer-and-transformer-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Shiva: The Destroyer and Transformer in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shiva, often translated as &amp;ldquo;The Auspicious One,&amp;rdquo; is one of the principal deities of Hinduism and a central figure in the Trimurti, the Hindu trinity which also includes Brahma (the creator) and Vishnu (the preserver). He is revered as the destroyer, transformer, and regenerator of the universe. This destruction, however, is not solely negative; it is viewed as a necessary catalyst for new creation and renewal, making Shiva a complex and multifaceted god. His key attributes include the third eye on his forehead, the crescent moon adorning his hair, the serpent Vasuki around his neck, the sacred Ganga flowing from his matted locks, and the trident (trishula) as his weapon. Shiva’s significance in Hinduism lies in his embodiment of the cyclical nature of existence and his profound connection to liberation (moksha).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vishnu</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vishnu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vishnu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vishnu-the-preserver-god-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Vishnu: The Preserver God in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vishnu, a central deity in Hinduism, is revered as the preserver and protector of the universe. He is one of the Trimurti, the Hindu trinity, alongside Brahma (the creator) and Shiva (the destroyer). Vishnu embodies the principles of dharma, karma, and moksha, playing a crucial role in maintaining cosmic order and ensuring the continuation of life. Often depicted with a serene countenance, adorned with royal garments, and carrying significant symbols, Vishnu is worshipped by millions of Hindus worldwide. His significance extends beyond simple preservation; he is also seen as the embodiment of divine love and compassion, intervening in the world through his avatars to restore balance when it is threatened by evil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
