<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/power/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Power on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/power/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Asura</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/asura/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/asura/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;asura-an-encyclopedic-overview&#34;&gt;Asura: An Encyclopedic Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Asuras, a prominent group of deities in Hindu cosmology, are often contrasted with the Devas. They are powerful, often ambitious beings who, while initially sharing a common ancestry with the Devas, are ultimately seen as forces of chaos and disruption that challenge the established order. While traditionally portrayed as antagonists to the Devas, particularly in later Hindu scriptures, the early Vedic texts present a more nuanced view, sometimes even associating Asuras with positive attributes such as power and creation. This article will explore the multifaceted nature of the Asuras, examining their origins, roles, representations, and significance within the broader context of Hindu thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indrani</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/indrani/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/indrani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;indrani-queen-of-the-gods-and-consort-of-indra&#34;&gt;Indrani: Queen of the Gods and Consort of Indra&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Indrani, also known as Shachi, is a prominent Hindu goddess and the consort of Indra, the king of the gods (Devas). She is revered as the queen of the celestial realm, Svarga, and embodies the ideal of a powerful and virtuous wife. Indrani represents conjugal bliss, strength, and prosperity, and plays a significant role in Hindu mythology and religious practices.  While not always the primary focus of individual worship like some other deities, her presence and influence are pervasive in the stories and rituals concerning Indra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
