<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bharatpur on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/categories/bharatpur/</link><description>Recent content in Bharatpur on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:57:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/categories/bharatpur/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bharatpur Bird Sanctuary: A Haven for Bird Lovers</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/rajasthan/bharatpur-bird-sanctuary-a-haven-for-bird-lovers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/rajasthan/bharatpur-bird-sanctuary-a-haven-for-bird-lovers/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bharatpur Bird Sanctuary, officially known as Keoladeo National Park, is a globally renowned avifauna haven nestled in the heart of Bharatpur district in Rajasthan, India. This UNESCO World Heritage site is located approximately 180 km (112 miles) south of Delhi and 55 km (34 miles) west of Agra, making it a convenient day trip or a stopover for those traveling between these popular tourist destinations. Situated at an average elevation of 174 meters (571 feet) above sea level, the sanctuary is a mosaic of wetlands, dry grasslands, woodlands, and human-modified habitats, making it a critical wintering ground for a myriad of migratory birds. Its unique appeal lies in the sheer diversity and density of birdlife, coupled with its easily accessible location and well-maintained trails, providing an unparalleled bird-watching experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Keoladeo National Park: A Birdwatcher's Paradise</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/rajasthan/keoladeo-national-park-a-birdwatchers-paradise/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/rajasthan/keoladeo-national-park-a-birdwatchers-paradise/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keoladeo National Park, also known as Bharatpur Bird Sanctuary, is a renowned UNESCO World Heritage site located in Bharatpur, Rajasthan, India. This avian paradise sprawls across approximately 29 square kilometers (11 sq mi), offering a vibrant haven for diverse bird species, both resident and migratory. Situated in the eastern part of Rajasthan, it sits at an elevation of about 174 meters (571 ft) above sea level. It is easily accessible from major cities like Delhi (approximately 180 km or 112 mi) and Agra (approximately 55 km or 34 mi), making it a popular day trip or weekend destination. What makes Keoladeo unique is its artificial wetland ecosystem, meticulously crafted by humans over a century ago, which has become a critical wintering ground for a vast array of birds, including some highly endangered species.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>