<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kurnool on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/categories/kurnool/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kurnool on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/categories/kurnool/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Belum Caves: A Remarkable Journey Through Time</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/andhra-pradesh/belum-caves-a-remarkable-journey-through-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/andhra-pradesh/belum-caves-a-remarkable-journey-through-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Belum Caves, a marvel of nature and one of the longest cave systems in the Indian subcontinent, lies nestled in the drought-prone district of Kurnool, Andhra Pradesh. Situated approximately 300 meters above sea level, these caves are a breathtaking testament to the power of geological processes and the subtle beauty of the subterranean world. Located about 270 km from Hyderabad and 30 km from the town of Tadipatri, Belum Caves offers a fascinating journey into the earth, showcasing stunning stalactite and stalagmite formations. The caves are unique for their length, accessibility, and the sheer grandeur of their underground chambers, making them a must-visit destination for adventurers, geology enthusiasts, and anyone seeking a unique travel experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gandikota Gorge: A Spectacular Cliffside Beauty Along Tungabhadra River</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/andhra-pradesh/gandikota-gorge-a-spectacular-cliffside-beauty-along-tungabhadra-river/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/andhra-pradesh/gandikota-gorge-a-spectacular-cliffside-beauty-along-tungabhadra-river/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gandikota Gorge, often referred to as the &amp;ldquo;Grand Canyon of India,&amp;rdquo; is a breathtaking natural wonder nestled in the Kurnool district of Andhra Pradesh, India. This dramatic gorge, carved by the Pennar River over millennia, presents a stunning visual spectacle of towering red granite cliffs that plunge into a deep, winding valley. Situated approximately 15 kilometers from Jammalamadugu and about 300 kilometers from Hyderabad, Gandikota offers a unique blend of history, adventure, and unparalleled scenic beauty. The elevation of the area is roughly 300-400 meters above sea level, making it a pleasant escape with relatively moderate temperatures. The area&amp;rsquo;s unique geological formations and historical significance make it a must-visit destination for travelers seeking adventure and natural beauty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
