<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Disease on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/disease/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Disease on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/disease/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shitala</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/shitala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/shitala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;shitala-the-goddess-of-healing-and-contagion-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Shitala: The Goddess of Healing and Contagion in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shitala (शीतला), also transliterated as Sheetala, is a revered Hindu goddess primarily associated with smallpox, chickenpox, measles, and other infectious diseases. While traditionally considered the cause of these ailments, she is simultaneously worshipped as the healer who can prevent and cure them. This duality reflects a complex understanding of disease within Hinduism, where the divine is often both the source and the solution. Shitala&amp;rsquo;s iconography typically depicts her as a graceful woman, often riding a donkey and holding a broom, a pot of cooling water, neem leaves, and sometimes a small bowl or cup. Her significance lies in her embodiment of the power to both inflict and alleviate suffering, making her a vital figure in the rural and traditional Hindu religious landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zarizari</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/zarizari/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/zarizari/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;zarizari-a-folk-deity-of-coastal-protection&#34;&gt;Zarizari: A Folk Deity of Coastal Protection&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zarizari is a regional Hindu folk deity primarily venerated in the coastal regions of India. Known predominantly as a protector against diseases, especially those affecting livestock and children, Zarizari occupies a unique space within the broader Hindu pantheon. Unlike deities found in the classical texts, Zarizari&amp;rsquo;s worship is rooted in local traditions and oral narratives, reflecting a more immediate and localized understanding of divine intervention and protection. Though specific iconography is not universally standardized, Zarizari is generally visualized as a powerful, protective figure, often associated with local materials and symbols representing health and prosperity. While not a prominent deity in mainstream Hinduism, Zarizari&amp;rsquo;s significance lies in providing comfort and security to communities facing health challenges, highlighting the adaptability and diversity of Hindu religious practices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
