<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Composite on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/composite/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Composite on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/composite/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ardhanari</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/ardhanari/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/ardhanari/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ardhanarishvara-the-androgynous-union-of-shiva-and-shakti&#34;&gt;Ardhanarishvara: The Androgynous Union of Shiva and Shakti&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ardhanarishvara (IAST: Ardhanārīśvara) is a composite androgynous form of the Hindu deities Shiva and Parvati (also known as Shakti). The deity is depicted as half male and half female, split down the middle. Typically, the right half is the male Shiva, adorned with his attributes, and the left half is the female Parvati, characterized by her features. Ardhanarishvara represents the synthesis of masculine and feminine energies, illustrating how Shiva and Shakti are inseparable aspects of the divine. The icon signifies the unity of opposites, the interdependence of Purusha (the male principle) and Prakriti (the female principle), and the essential harmony required for creation and sustenance of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hari Hara</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/hari-hara/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/hari-hara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hari-hara-the-unified-divinity-of-vishnu-and-shiva&#34;&gt;Hari Hara: The Unified Divinity of Vishnu and Shiva&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hari Hara is a syncretic deity in Hinduism, representing a combined form of Vishnu (Hari) and Shiva (Hara). This deity embodies the concept of the essential unity of these two major Hindu gods, often portrayed as complementary aspects of the same ultimate reality (Brahman). Hari Hara&amp;rsquo;s iconography typically presents a single figure, half representing Vishnu and the other half representing Shiva, highlighting the interconnectedness and non-duality within the Hindu pantheon. The significance of Hari Hara lies in its symbolic representation of harmony, balance, and the ultimate unity of seemingly disparate aspects of the divine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
