<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sivasagar on Beautiful India</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/sivasagar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sivasagar on Beautiful India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/sivasagar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rang Gompa: A Hub of Buddhist Spirituality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/assam/rang-gompa-a-hub-of-buddhist-spirituality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/assam/rang-gompa-a-hub-of-buddhist-spirituality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sivasagar, also known as Sibsagar, is a historical town situated in the Sivasagar district of Assam, India. Nestled along the banks of the Dikhow River, Sivasagar (meaning &amp;ldquo;Ocean of Shiva&amp;rdquo;) holds immense historical significance as it served as the capital of the Ahom kingdom from 1699 to 1788. Its strategic location in Upper Assam, with an elevation of approximately 91 meters (300 feet) above sea level, provides a captivating blend of historical grandeur and natural beauty. Sivasagar offers a unique glimpse into the rich cultural heritage of Assam, boasting stunning architectural marvels and a deep-rooted connection to the Ahom dynasty. It’s strategically located near other popular destinations like Jorhat (approx. 55 km) and Kaziranga National Park (approx. 120 km), making it a convenient base for exploring the region. Sivasagar is a treasure trove of history, culture, and scenic landscapes, making it a captivating destination for travelers seeking to delve into Assam&amp;rsquo;s rich past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
