<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Folk Hero on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/folk-hero/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Folk Hero on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/folk-hero/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Devnarayan</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/devnarayan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/devnarayan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;devnarayan-a-folk-deity-and-incarnation-of-vishnu&#34;&gt;Devnarayan: A Folk Deity and Incarnation of Vishnu&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Devnarayan is a prominent folk deity primarily worshipped in Rajasthan, India. He is revered as an avatar (incarnation) of the Hindu god Vishnu, the preserver in the Hindu trinity. Devnarayan&amp;rsquo;s significance lies in his role as a protector, healer, and upholder of dharma within the communities that venerate him. His iconography typically includes depictions of him riding a horse, often accompanied by his brothers or attendants, wielding weapons and exuding a regal presence. Devnarayan&amp;rsquo;s worship blends elements of Vaishnavism with local traditions, making him a unique figure within the broader Hindu landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tejaji</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/tejaji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/tejaji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tejaji-the-snake-protecting-folk-deity-of-rajasthan&#34;&gt;Tejaji: The Snake-Protecting Folk Deity of Rajasthan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tejaji, also known as Veer Tejaji, is a revered folk deity primarily worshipped in Rajasthan, India. He is widely recognized as a protector of cows, a defender of the oppressed, and a figure associated with snakes and their venom. Tejaji&amp;rsquo;s iconography typically depicts him as a courageous warrior, often shown riding a mare and being bitten by a serpent on his tongue. His widespread popularity stems from his perceived ability to cure snake bites and provide protection from various ailments. While not directly derived from classical Hindu scriptures, Tejaji represents a vibrant example of local traditions and syncretism within the broader Hindu religious landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
