<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sindhi on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/sindhi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sindhi on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/sindhi/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cheti Chand</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/cheti-chand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/cheti-chand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jhulelal-jayanti-celebrating-new-beginnings-and-the-miraculous-saint-of-the-sindhis&#34;&gt;Jhulelal Jayanti: Celebrating New Beginnings and the Miraculous Saint of the Sindhis&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever felt the thrill of a new beginning, the promise of fresh starts hanging in the air? In the vibrant tapestry of Indian festivals, few embody this spirit quite like Cheti Chand, the Sindhi New Year. It&amp;rsquo;s more than just a calendar shift; it&amp;rsquo;s a jubilant celebration honoring the birth of Ishtadeva Uderolal, affectionately known as Jhulelal, the patron saint of the Sindhi community. For Sindhis around the world, Cheti Chand is a potent reminder of resilience, faith, and the enduring power of cultural identity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jhulelal</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/jhulelal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/jhulelal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jhulelal-the-river-deity-of-the-sindhi-hindus&#34;&gt;Jhulelal: The River Deity of the Sindhi Hindus&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jhulelal is the most revered deity of the Sindhi Hindus, a community with roots in the Sindh province of present-day Pakistan. He is primarily associated with the Indus River, which holds immense cultural and religious significance for the Sindhi people. Jhulelal is considered a manifestation of God, often regarded as a protector and deliverer of the Sindhi community during times of oppression. His iconography often depicts him as a young man riding atop a fish or crocodile, holding a lotus flower, and symbolizing hope, courage, and divine grace. Jhulelal&amp;rsquo;s significance in Hinduism lies in his role as a unifier of the Sindhi identity, a symbol of resistance against injustice, and a representation of the omnipresent divine power, particularly connected to the vital force of water.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
