<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sikh on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/sikh/</link><description>Recent content in Sikh on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:55:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/sikh/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gurupurab</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/gurupurab/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/gurupurab/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="gurupurab-illuminating-the-world-with-love-and-service"&gt;Gurupurab: Illuminating the World with Love and Service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever experienced a festival that feels like a warm embrace, a beacon of hope, and a celebration of selfless service, all rolled into one? Then you need to learn about Gurupurab, the Sikh festival commemorating the birth anniversaries of the Gurus, especially Guru Nanak Dev Ji, the founder of Sikhism. Growing up, Gurupurab was always a highlight of the year. The air filled with the melodic hymns, the aroma of freshly cooked langar wafted through the streets, and a sense of community and togetherness enveloped everything.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Holla Mohalla</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/holla-mohalla/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/holla-mohalla/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="holla-mohalla-where-sikh-bravery--vibrant-spectacle-ignite-the-spirit"&gt;Holla Mohalla: Where Sikh Bravery &amp;amp; Vibrant Spectacle Ignite the Spirit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a festival overflowing with the energy of a thousand charging horses, the clang of steel meeting steel, and the vibrant colours of spring painting the sky. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just Holi’s after-party; it&amp;rsquo;s Holla Mohalla, a dazzling display of Sikh martial prowess and unwavering spirit that unfolds annually in Anandpur Sahib, Punjab. For centuries, this unique festival has been more than just a celebration; it&amp;rsquo;s a testament to the Sikh values of courage, community, and devotion to the Divine.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>