<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Semi-Divine on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/semi-divine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Semi-Divine on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/semi-divine/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Yaksha</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/yaksha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/yaksha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;yaksha-nature-spirits-of-wealth-and-guardians-of-hidden-treasures&#34;&gt;Yaksha: Nature Spirits of Wealth and Guardians of Hidden Treasures&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yaksha (Sanskrit: यक्ष) are a broad class of nature spirits in Hindu, Buddhist, and Jain mythology, generally benevolent, who are associated with wealth, fertility, natural treasures, and the protection of forests, mountains, and water bodies. While not deities in the highest echelon of the Hindu pantheon like Vishnu or Shiva, they are powerful beings, often seen as attendants of Kubera, the god of wealth, and are revered for their ability to bestow prosperity and grant wishes. Their iconography varies, but they are often depicted as well-built, powerful figures, sometimes with bulging eyes and sharp teeth, reflecting their primal connection to the natural world. Yakshas play a significant role in Hindu cosmology, appearing in various scriptures and influencing art, literature, and religious practices throughout the Indian subcontinent. They are often seen as intermediary figures between humans and the higher gods, capable of influencing human fortunes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
