<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>New Tehri on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/categories/new-tehri/</link><description>Recent content in New Tehri on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:57:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/categories/new-tehri/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tehri Dam: A Majestic Engineering Marvel in Uttarakhand</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/uttarakhand/tehri-dam-a-majestic-engineering-marvel-in-uttarakhand/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/uttarakhand/tehri-dam-a-majestic-engineering-marvel-in-uttarakhand/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tehri Dam, located in New Tehri, Uttarakhand, India, is not just a marvel of engineering but also a gateway to the stunning landscapes of the Garhwal Himalayas. Situated at a high altitude, this colossal dam is nestled amidst picturesque mountains and offers breathtaking views of the turquoise waters of the Tehri Lake. New Tehri, the planned town that arose to accommodate those displaced by the dam&amp;rsquo;s construction, is perched at an elevation of approximately 1,750 meters (5,740 feet) above sea level. It is easily accessible from popular destinations like Rishikesh (around 75 km) and Dehradun (about 100 km), making it a convenient stop for travelers exploring Uttarakhand. The dam itself is the tallest in India and one of the tallest in the world, creating a vast reservoir that reshaped the landscape. This makes Tehri Dam a unique destination combining natural beauty with the awe-inspiring scale of human achievement.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>