<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Odisha on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/odisha/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Odisha on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/odisha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jagannath</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/jagannath/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/jagannath/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jagannath-lord-of-the-universe&#34;&gt;Jagannath: Lord of the Universe&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jagannath, literally translated as &amp;ldquo;Lord of the Universe,&amp;rdquo; is a central Hindu deity, particularly revered in the state of Odisha, India. He is primarily understood as a form of Vishnu or Krishna, embodying universal consciousness and supreme divinity. Jagannath is worshipped alongside his siblings, Balabhadra (Balarama), considered his elder brother, and Subhadra, his sister. Their iconic wooden images, distinct from conventional Hindu iconography, are characterized by large eyes, rudimentary limbs, and a vibrant color scheme. The annual Rath Yatra, or chariot festival, where the deities are transported in massive, elaborately decorated chariots, is a globally recognized spectacle and a testament to Jagannath&amp;rsquo;s profound significance within Hinduism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuakhai</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/nuakhai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/nuakhai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nuakhai-a-taste-of-new-beginnings-in-western-odisha&#34;&gt;Nuakhai: A Taste of New Beginnings in Western Odisha&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine waking up to the aroma of freshly harvested rice cooking in earthen pots, the vibrant colours of Rangoli adorning courtyards, and the rhythmic beat of drums echoing through the air. This is Nuakhai, a festival that throbs with life, gratitude, and the promise of abundance in the heart of Western Odisha and surrounding regions. It’s more than just a harvest festival; it’s a celebration of community, family, and the enduring bond between humans and the land.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pana Sankranti</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/pana-sankranti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/pana-sankranti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;welcome-the-sun-welcome-the-new-year-unveiling-the-magic-of-pana-sankranti-in-odisha&#34;&gt;Welcome the Sun, Welcome the New Year: Unveiling the Magic of Pana Sankranti in Odisha&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The air crackles with anticipation, a symphony of drums echoes through the streets, and the scent of freshly bloomed mango blossoms hangs heavy in the breeze. It’s a time of vibrant colours, joyous gatherings, and the sweet, refreshing taste of &lt;em&gt;pana&lt;/em&gt;. No, I’m not painting a scene from a fairytale – I’m describing Pana Sankranti, the Odia New Year, a festival that resonates with the heart of Odisha and its people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Samaleswari</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/samaleswari/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/samaleswari/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;samaleswari-a-regional-goddess-of-odisha&#34;&gt;Samaleswari: A Regional Goddess of Odisha&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Samaleswari is a prominent regional Hindu goddess predominantly worshipped in the state of Odisha, India, particularly in the western part of the state. She is considered the presiding deity (Ishtadevi) of Sambalpur and the surrounding region. Samaleswari is generally regarded as a powerful manifestation of Shakti, representing both creative and destructive forces. Her iconography typically features a fierce form, often adorned with symbolic weapons and ornaments, representing her protective and sovereign nature. Her worship is deeply ingrained in the cultural and religious fabric of Odisha, influencing art, music, and social traditions. While not widely mentioned in pan-Indian scriptures, her significance within the Odia community is profound.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
