<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mothers on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/mothers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mothers on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/mothers/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ahoi Ashtami</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/ahoi-ashtami/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/ahoi-ashtami/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ahoi-ashtami-a-mothers-unwavering-love-painted-on-the-canvas-of-faith&#34;&gt;Ahoi Ashtami: A Mother&amp;rsquo;s Unwavering Love Painted on the Canvas of Faith&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine the soft glow of earthen lamps flickering against the backdrop of a star-studded night. The air hums with whispered prayers, the gentle clinking of bangles, and the sweet aroma of freshly prepared delicacies. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just a pretty picture; it&amp;rsquo;s Ahoi Ashtami, a festival deeply etched in the hearts of Indian mothers, a testament to their unwavering love and fervent prayers for the well-being of their children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jitiya</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/jitiya/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/jitiya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jitiya-a-mothers-unwavering-love--the-thread-of-tradition&#34;&gt;Jitiya: A Mother&amp;rsquo;s Unwavering Love &amp;amp; the Thread of Tradition&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever encountered a love so profound, so deeply rooted, that it manifested as an unwavering fast, a silent prayer woven with unwavering devotion? Welcome to Jitiya, a vibrant and emotionally charged festival celebrated primarily in Bihar, Jharkhand, and parts of Nepal. It’s a testament to the powerful bond between a mother and her child, a celebration of fertility, protection, and the enduring strength of maternal love. For someone unfamiliar with the tapestry of Indian festivals, Jitiya might seem austere with its focus on fasting. But delve deeper, and you&amp;rsquo;ll find a rich tapestry of traditions, folklore, and an unbreakable thread connecting generations of women. I remember growing up watching my own mother observe this fast. The determination etched on her face, the quiet prayers whispered under her breath – it left an indelible impression on me, a testament to a mother’s relentless dedication. Jitiya is more than just a festival; it’s a living embodiment of a mother’s love, passed down through generations like a cherished heirloom. Prepare to be moved by the dedication, the vibrant colors, and the poignant stories that make Jitiya a truly unforgettable celebration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jivitputrika</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/jivitputrika/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/jivitputrika/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jivitputrika-a-mothers-unwavering-love-fasted-in-faith&#34;&gt;Jivitputrika: A Mother&amp;rsquo;s Unwavering Love, Fasted in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a scene filled with hushed anticipation, the aroma of traditional delicacies gently wafting through the air, and the vibrant colors of sarees shimmering under the morning sun. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just another day; it&amp;rsquo;s Jivitputrika, or Jitiya, a powerful and deeply moving festival celebrated predominantly in the Indian states of Bihar, Jharkhand, Uttar Pradesh, and West Bengal. But this isn&amp;rsquo;t your typical celebratory feast; it&amp;rsquo;s a testament to a mother&amp;rsquo;s unwavering devotion and sacrifice for her children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
