<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shakti on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/shakti/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shakti on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/shakti/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bhairavi</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/bhairavi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/bhairavi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bhairavi-the-fierce-goddess-of-dissolution-and-renewal&#34;&gt;Bhairavi: The Fierce Goddess of Dissolution and Renewal&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bhairavi is a fierce and formidable manifestation of Goddess Parvati, the consort of Lord Shiva and the embodiment of Shakti, the divine feminine energy. Often depicted as a powerful and wrathful figure, Bhairavi represents the destructive and transformative aspects of the divine. Her iconography is laden with symbolism relating to death, destruction, and the transcendence of fear, ultimately leading to liberation and spiritual awakening. While fearsome in appearance, Bhairavi&amp;rsquo;s role within the Hindu pantheon is crucial for maintaining cosmic balance by dissolving negativity and paving the way for renewal. She is primarily associated with Shaktism, the Hindu tradition that reveres the Goddess as the supreme divine power.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devi</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/devi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/devi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;devi-the-supreme-goddess-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Devi: The Supreme Goddess in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Devi, meaning &amp;ldquo;Goddess,&amp;rdquo; is the supreme deity in Hinduism, representing the feminine aspect of the divine. She is often understood as the ultimate power, the dynamic energy (Shakti) that underlies the universe. Devi is not merely a consort or a female counterpart to a male god; rather, she embodies the totality of existence and is considered the source of all creation, sustenance, and destruction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
