<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Worship on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/worship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Worship on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/worship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hanuman Jayanti</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/hanuman-jayanti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/hanuman-jayanti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hanuman-jayanti-a-celebration-of-strength-devotion-and-the-monkey-god&#34;&gt;Hanuman Jayanti: A Celebration of Strength, Devotion, and the Monkey God&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a day filled with the rhythmic chanting of mantras, the aroma of freshly baked sweets, and the vibrant colors of ochre and vermillion adorning every temple. This is Hanuman Jayanti, a day dedicated to celebrating the birth of Lord Hanuman, a revered deity in Hinduism known for his unparalleled devotion, unwavering strength, and boundless perseverance. It’s more than just a birthday; it’s a powerful reminder of the qualities we should all strive for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Padwa (Diwali)</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/padwa-diwali/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/padwa-diwali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;beyond-the-lights-unveiling-the-heart-of-padwa--a-diwali-celebration-you-might-be-missing&#34;&gt;Beyond the Lights: Unveiling the Heart of Padwa – A Diwali Celebration You Might Be Missing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diwali, the festival of lights, is universally known for its dazzling displays, delicious sweets, and the joyous spirit of homecoming. But have you ever stopped to wonder about the day &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the grand finale? That’s when the celebration continues, taking on a new dimension with Padwa, also known as Govardhan Puja or Bali Pratipada. While the rest of the world might be packing away decorations and cleaning up remnants of the festivities, in India, Padwa marks a fresh start, a celebration of prosperity, and a reminder of the enduring power of good over evil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tulsi Pujan Diwas</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/tulsi-pujan-diwas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/tulsi-pujan-diwas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-sacred-union-celebrating-tulsi-pujan-diwas-the-divine-marriage-of-plant-and-god&#34;&gt;A Sacred Union: Celebrating Tulsi Pujan Diwas, the Divine Marriage of Plant and God&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine the crisp December air, tinged with the fragrance of incense and the sweet aroma of freshly prepared sweets. Picture a vibrant green plant, adorned with marigolds and shimmering tinsel, standing tall in a courtyard, bathed in the soft glow of oil lamps. This is a snapshot of Tulsi Pujan Diwas, a celebration deeply woven into the fabric of Hinduism, where the sacred Tulsi (holy basil) plant is revered and symbolically married to Lord Vishnu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
