<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yoga on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/yoga/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Yoga on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/yoga/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dattatreya</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/dattatreya/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/dattatreya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;dattatreya-the-unified-divine-principle-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Dattatreya: The Unified Divine Principle in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dattatreya is a prominent Hindu deity, widely revered as an incarnation (avatar) of the divine trinity – Brahma (the creator), Vishnu (the preserver), and Shiva (the destroyer). This unique amalgamation represents the unified principle of the universe, embodying creation, maintenance, and transformation. Dattatreya is often depicted as a serene yogi, representing renunciation and wisdom, yet he also embodies the powers of all three major deities. His worship is prevalent across various Hindu traditions, and he is regarded as a guru, a yogi, and a compassionate benefactor of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yogeshvara</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/yogeshvara/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/yogeshvara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;yogeshvara-lord-of-yoga-and-meditation-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Yogeshvara: Lord of Yoga and Meditation in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yogeshvara, meaning &amp;ldquo;Lord of Yoga,&amp;rdquo; is a significant aspect of Shiva within Hinduism, particularly revered as the supreme master of yoga, meditation, and spiritual discipline. This form of Shiva embodies the ultimate goal of yoga – the union of the individual soul (Atman) with the universal consciousness (Brahman). Yogeshvara represents the power of introspection, self-control, and transcendence, offering devotees a path towards liberation (moksha) through rigorous spiritual practice. He is often depicted in meditative postures, signifying the stillness and focus required for inner realization. The worship of Yogeshvara emphasizes the practical application of yogic principles in daily life, leading to physical, mental, and spiritual well-being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
