<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sun on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/sun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sun on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/sun/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aruna</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/aruna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/aruna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;aruna-the-dawns-charioteer-in-hindu-cosmology&#34;&gt;Aruna: The Dawn&amp;rsquo;s Charioteer in Hindu Cosmology&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aruna, in Hinduism, is the personification of the reddish glow of the rising sun, specifically associated with the dawn. He is more than just a representation of this celestial phenomenon; he is a significant deity in his own right, believed to possess spiritual powers and play a crucial role in guiding the sun god, Surya, across the sky. Typically depicted as a charioteer, Aruna’s most prominent attribute is his limblessness or diminished physical form. His iconography consistently portrays him driving Surya’s chariot, an image central to his significance in Hindu mythology. Aruna represents the transition from darkness to light, embodying hope, anticipation, and the promise of a new day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushan</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/pushan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/pushan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;pushan-the-guardian-of-roads-and-livestock&#34;&gt;Pushan: The Guardian of Roads and Livestock&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pushan, also spelled Pusan, is a prominent solar deity in the Hindu pantheon, primarily associated with journeys, roads, livestock, and general prosperity. He is often invoked for safe travel, finding lost objects, and ensuring the well-being of cattle, which were vital to the ancient Vedic economy and lifestyle. Pushan represents a benevolent and nurturing aspect of the Sun, guiding and protecting those who rely on his grace. He is a significant, albeit less frequently worshipped today, figure whose role highlights the importance of safe passage, prosperity, and the connection to the land in Vedic and early Hindu thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surya</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/surya/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/surya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;surya-the-radiant-sun-god-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Surya: The Radiant Sun God in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Surya, the Sun god, is a major deity in Hinduism, revered as the source of light, warmth, and life on Earth. Often depicted riding a golden chariot pulled by seven horses, Surya embodies energy, illumination, and vitality. He is a vital force in the cosmos, responsible for the cycle of day and night, seasons, and the overall well-being of the world. Surya&amp;rsquo;s influence extends beyond the physical realm, encompassing spiritual enlightenment and dispelling ignorance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vivasvat</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vivasvat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vivasvat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vivasvat-the-radiant-sun-god-of-hinduism&#34;&gt;Vivasvat: The Radiant Sun God of Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vivasvat, also spelled Vivashvan, is a significant solar deity in Hinduism, often identified as another name for Surya, the sun god. He embodies the radiant and illuminating aspects of the sun, representing its life-giving energy and power. While often considered synonymous with Surya, Vivasvat carries specific connotations related to his brilliance and historical significance within Hindu mythology and lineage. He is revered as the progenitor of humanity and a key figure in the dissemination of sacred knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
