<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Siblings on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/siblings/</link><description>Recent content in Siblings on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:55:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/siblings/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bhai Dooj</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/bhai-dooj/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/bhai-dooj/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="bhai-dooj-a-celebration-of-sibling-love-that-shines-brighter-than-diwali"&gt;Bhai Dooj: A Celebration of Sibling Love That Shines Brighter Than Diwali&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a festival bathed in the golden glow of autumn, filled with laughter, delicious aromas, and a tangible feeling of warmth. That’s Bhai Dooj, a beautiful Indian celebration that takes place right after Diwali, focusing on the cherished bond between brothers and sisters. While Diwali is the festival of lights, Bhai Dooj is the festival of sibling love, a day dedicated to strengthening ties and showering blessings upon each other. Forget presents and superficial gestures; Bhai Dooj is about genuine affection, protection, and a promise to always be there for each other, through thick and thin.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Raksha Bandhan</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/raksha-bandhan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/raksha-bandhan/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="raksha-bandhan-a-thread-of-love-a-promise-of-protection"&gt;Raksha Bandhan: A Thread of Love, A Promise of Protection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The air hums with anticipation, sweets are being prepared, and colorful threads shimmer like captured rainbows. It&amp;rsquo;s Raksha Bandhan, one of India&amp;rsquo;s most beloved festivals, and the feeling in the air is palpable. It&amp;rsquo;s a day steeped in tradition, bursting with vibrant colors, and overflowing with love and the enduring bond between brothers and sisters. But Raksha Bandhan is more than just tying a decorative thread. It&amp;rsquo;s a powerful expression of affection, a reaffirmation of familial responsibility, and a celebration of the unwavering connection that siblings share.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>