<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Preserver on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/preserver/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Preserver on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/preserver/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Acyutah</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/acyutah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/acyutah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;acyutah-the-infallible-aspect-of-vishnu&#34;&gt;Acyutah: The Infallible Aspect of Vishnu&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acyutah, a significant name of Vishnu within the Hindu pantheon, signifies the “unfallen,” “infallible,” or “imperishable” aspect of the preserver deity. This name emphasizes Vishnu&amp;rsquo;s unwavering nature, his unchanging essence, and his perpetual role in upholding cosmic order (dharma). Acyutah embodies the immutable truth and the eternal presence of the divine in the universe. His key attribute is his unwavering commitment to dharma, manifested through his various avatars and actions. Iconographically, Acyutah is generally depicted as Vishnu, bearing the traditional symbols of the conch shell (Shankha), discus (Chakra), lotus (Padma), and mace (Gada), representing his power, knowledge, auspiciousness, and authority, respectively. His significance lies in reminding devotees of the eternal and unchanging nature of the divine, a source of solace and guidance amidst the transient nature of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hari</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/hari/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/hari/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hari-a-comprehensive-overview-of-the-remover-of-sins-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Hari: A Comprehensive Overview of the Remover of Sins in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hari, a significant name in Hinduism, is primarily used as a designation for Vishnu and his avatar Krishna. The term signifies &amp;ldquo;the remover of sins,&amp;rdquo; highlighting one of the core aspects of the deity&amp;rsquo;s role: to liberate devotees from the cycle of karma and guide them towards liberation (moksha). Hari is revered as the preserver of the universe and a protector of dharma (righteousness). Iconographically, Hari often appears in human form, adorned with royal garments, holding symbols of power and auspiciousness, and sometimes depicted with a blue complexion, reflecting his cosmic nature. His significance in Hinduism stems from his association with maintaining cosmic order, granting grace to his devotees, and embodying the divine qualities of love, compassion, and justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perumal</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/perumal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/perumal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;perumal-a-south-indian-manifestation-of-vishnu&#34;&gt;Perumal: A South Indian Manifestation of Vishnu&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Perumal, also spelled Thirumal, is a prominent name for Vishnu, the preserver deity in the Hindu Trimurti (the Hindu trinity), particularly prevalent in South Indian, specifically Tamil, traditions. Representing the sustaining force of the universe, Perumal embodies righteousness, protection, and the ultimate reality. He is revered as the source of all creation and the upholder of dharma. Perumal&amp;rsquo;s key attributes include his divine consort Lakshmi (or Sri) representing wealth and prosperity, and his association with qualities of compassion, justice, and universal love. Iconographically, Perumal is often depicted in majestic forms, adorned with precious ornaments and wielding powerful divine weapons. His significance lies in his ability to incarnate in various avatars to restore balance and guide humanity toward spiritual liberation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vishnu</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vishnu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vishnu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vishnu-the-preserver-god-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Vishnu: The Preserver God in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vishnu, a central deity in Hinduism, is revered as the preserver and protector of the universe. He is one of the Trimurti, the Hindu trinity, alongside Brahma (the creator) and Shiva (the destroyer). Vishnu embodies the principles of dharma, karma, and moksha, playing a crucial role in maintaining cosmic order and ensuring the continuation of life. Often depicted with a serene countenance, adorned with royal garments, and carrying significant symbols, Vishnu is worshipped by millions of Hindus worldwide. His significance extends beyond simple preservation; he is also seen as the embodiment of divine love and compassion, intervening in the world through his avatars to restore balance when it is threatened by evil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
