<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Planet on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/planet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Planet on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/planet/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Budha</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/budha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/budha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;budha-the-hindu-god-of-mercury&#34;&gt;Budha: The Hindu God of Mercury&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Budha, also known as Saumya, is the Hindu god associated with the planet Mercury. He is regarded as the deity of wit, intelligence, commerce, and communication. Often depicted as a youthful and handsome figure, Budha influences the mental and intellectual capacities of individuals. He is venerated as one of the nine Navagrahas (nine celestial bodies) in Hindu astrology and is believed to have a significant impact on one&amp;rsquo;s life based on his position in the birth chart.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mangala</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/mangala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/mangala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mangala-the-fiery-god-of-mars-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Mangala: The Fiery God of Mars in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mangala, also known as Angaraka, is the Hindu god associated with the planet Mars (Mangala Graha). He is a deity representing energy, ambition, courage, and strength, often depicted as a fiery and powerful warrior. Mangala embodies the qualities of action, leadership, and perseverance.  His influence is believed to significantly affect human affairs, particularly in matters of courage, war, and real estate. In Hindu astrology, Mangala&amp;rsquo;s position in a birth chart is analyzed for its impact on an individual&amp;rsquo;s temperament and life events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rahu</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/rahu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/rahu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;rahu-the-shadow-planet-in-hindu-cosmology&#34;&gt;Rahu: The Shadow Planet in Hindu Cosmology&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rahu is a significant celestial entity in Hinduism, categorized as one of the &lt;em&gt;Navagrahas&lt;/em&gt; (nine planets). Unlike other planets that represent physical celestial bodies, Rahu is a shadow planet, representing the north lunar node, the point where the Moon&amp;rsquo;s orbit crosses the ecliptic. Rahu is a powerful force, often associated with eclipses, chaos, confusion, ambition, and worldly desires. Iconographically, Rahu is typically depicted as a serpent&amp;rsquo;s head with no body, often riding a lion or black horse. His presence is considered to have a profound impact on astrological charts and is often viewed with a degree of apprehension due to its association with karmic debts and challenging life events. Rahu&amp;rsquo;s significance lies in its ability to obfuscate and influence human perception, pushing individuals towards material pursuits and questioning established norms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shani</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/shani/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/shani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;shani-the-lord-of-karma-and-justice&#34;&gt;Shani: The Lord of Karma and Justice&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shani, also known as Śanaiścara, is a prominent Hindu deity associated with the planet Saturn (Śani). Revered as the dispenser of justice and the lord of karma, Shani&amp;rsquo;s influence on an individual&amp;rsquo;s life is considered profound. He is neither inherently benevolent nor malevolent, but rather a force of cosmic balance, rewarding righteous actions and punishing wrongdoing. His key attributes include a slow pace (Śanaiścara literally means &amp;ldquo;slow-moving&amp;rdquo;), discipline, austerity, and profound wisdom born of experience. Iconographically, Shani is often depicted as dark in complexion, adorned with black clothing, and riding a crow or buffalo. In Hinduism, Shani holds significant importance as a judge of moral behavior and a facilitator of spiritual growth through karmic retribution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
