<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Architect on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/architect/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Architect on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/architect/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vishvakarman</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vishvakarman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vishvakarman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vishvakarman-the-divine-architect-and-craftsman-of-the-universe&#34;&gt;Vishvakarman: The Divine Architect and Craftsman of the Universe&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vishvakarman, also spelled Vishwakarma, is a prominent deity in Hinduism revered as the divine architect, craftsman, and engineer of the universe. Often described as the &amp;ldquo;divine carpenter&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;master of all crafts,&amp;rdquo; he is credited with designing and constructing the palaces of the gods, their weapons, and other celestial objects. He embodies skill, ingenuity, and the creative power necessary for building and shaping the cosmos. His importance lies not just in his craft, but also in his role as a personification of the creative energy that underlies all existence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vishwakarma</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vishwakarma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vishwakarma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vishwakarma-the-divine-architect-and-craftsman&#34;&gt;Vishwakarma: The Divine Architect and Craftsman&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vishwakarma, also known as the divine architect and craftsman, occupies a significant position in the Hindu pantheon. He is revered as the master of all crafts and the builder of the palaces of the gods. Depicted as a skilled artisan, he is often credited with creating the weapons, tools, and infrastructure used by both gods and demons. His association with creation, innovation, and craftsmanship makes him a particularly important deity for artisans, engineers, and architects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
