<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Purity on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/purity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Purity on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/purity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Arundhati</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/arundhati/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/arundhati/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;arundhati-embodiment-of-virtue-and-constancy&#34;&gt;Arundhati: Embodiment of Virtue and Constancy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;** Introduction**&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arundhati is a revered figure in Hinduism, primarily recognized as the wife of the esteemed sage Vashishta. She is not considered a goddess in the traditional sense, but rather a woman of exceptional virtue, devotion, and unwavering fidelity. She is intrinsically linked to the Saptarishi, the seven great sages, and is often identified with the morning star and the Alcor star, a faint companion star to Mizar in the constellation Ursa Major (the Big Dipper). Arundhati serves as an exemplar of marital devotion, chastity, and asceticism, making her a significant figure in Hindu traditions relating to marriage, family, and spiritual life. While not receiving widespread temple worship, her veneration lies in the symbolic representation of ideal womanhood and the invocation of her name in marriage rituals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gauri</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/gauri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/gauri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;gauri-the-auspicious-golden-one&#34;&gt;Gauri: The Auspicious Golden One&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gauri, a revered Hindu goddess, is considered the golden and radiant aspect of Parvati, the consort of Lord Shiva. Representing purity, austerity, and marital bliss, Gauri embodies the ideal of womanhood in Hinduism. Her iconography often depicts her as a beautiful and benevolent goddess, adorned in golden attire and exuding grace. She is primarily worshipped for marital harmony, fertility, and overall prosperity. Her significance lies in her portrayal as the complete woman, perfectly balanced in her devotion, strength, and beauty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sita</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/sita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/sita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;sita-embodiment-of-virtue-and-feminine-ideal-in-hindu-tradition&#34;&gt;Sita: Embodiment of Virtue and Feminine Ideal in Hindu Tradition&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sita, also known as Janaki, is a central figure in Hinduism, revered as the consort of Lord Rama and an embodiment of wifely devotion, feminine virtue, and strength in adversity. She is a primary deity in the Vaishnava tradition, embodying Lakshmi, the goddess of prosperity and auspiciousness. Sita&amp;rsquo;s life, as narrated primarily in the epic Ramayana, serves as a potent symbol of purity, self-sacrifice, and unwavering commitment to dharma. Her iconography usually depicts her as a beautiful and graceful woman, often adorned with traditional Indian attire, standing alongside Rama or in a gesture of offering. Sita&amp;rsquo;s significance lies not only in her divine status but also in the profound ethical and spiritual lessons she imparts through her story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
