<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tourism on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/tourism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tourism on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/tourism/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dwijing Festival</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/dwijing-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/dwijing-festival/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;awaken-your-senses-discover-the-magic-of-assams-dwijing-festival&#34;&gt;Awaken Your Senses: Discover the Magic of Assam&amp;rsquo;s Dwijing Festival&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a kaleidoscope of colors exploding against the backdrop of a serene river, the air filled with the rhythmic beat of traditional drums and the tantalizing aroma of local delicacies. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a scene from a movie; it&amp;rsquo;s the Dwijing Festival, a vibrant celebration that transforms the banks of the Aie River in Assam into a captivating spectacle of culture, tourism, and community spirit. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for an authentic Indian experience that goes beyond the usual tourist trails, Dwijing is a hidden gem waiting to be discovered.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elephant Festival</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/elephant-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/elephant-festival/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;trunkloads-of-tradition-unveiling-the-majesty-of-jaipurs-elephant-festival&#34;&gt;Trunkloads of Tradition: Unveiling the Majesty of Jaipur&amp;rsquo;s Elephant Festival&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a kaleidoscope of vibrant colours, the majestic rumble of gentle giants adorned in shimmering silks, and the infectious energy of a city celebrating its deep connection to a sacred animal. This is the Elephant Festival of Jaipur, a spectacle that transcends mere entertainment and plunges you into the heart of Rajasthani culture. I remember the first time I witnessed it – the sheer scale of the event, the intricate designs painted on the elephants, the joyous cries of the crowd – it was an experience that stayed with me long after I left the Pink City.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
