<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Shivamogga on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/categories/shivamogga/</link><description>Recent content in Shivamogga on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:57:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/categories/shivamogga/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bhadra Wildlife Sanctuary: A Top Biodiversity Hotspot in Karnataka</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/karnataka/bhadra-wildlife-sanctuary-a-top-biodiversity-hotspot-in-karnataka/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/karnataka/bhadra-wildlife-sanctuary-a-top-biodiversity-hotspot-in-karnataka/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bhadra Wildlife Sanctuary, a jewel nestled in the Western Ghats of Karnataka, offers an enchanting blend of lush landscapes, vibrant wildlife, and tranquil surroundings. Situated in the Shivamogga district, it provides an escape into nature&amp;rsquo;s embrace. With an average elevation ranging from 750 to 1875 meters above sea level, the sanctuary is a haven for biodiversity. It’s conveniently located near other popular destinations like Chikmagalur and Shimoga, making it an accessible yet secluded retreat. What makes Bhadra unique is its diverse ecosystem, which supports a rich variety of flora and fauna, including the majestic Bengal tiger and the elusive black panther. It provides a perfect balance of adventure and relaxation for nature enthusiasts and wildlife lovers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jog Falls: A Must-Visit Waterfall in Karnataka</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/karnataka/jog-falls-a-must-visit-waterfall-in-karnataka/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/karnataka/jog-falls-a-must-visit-waterfall-in-karnataka/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jog Falls, also known as Gerusoppa Falls or Joga Falls, is a majestic waterfall located in the Shimoga district of Karnataka, India. This breathtaking natural wonder is formed by the Sharavathi River, cascading down a height of 253 meters (830 feet), making it one of the highest plunge waterfalls in India and a sight to behold, especially during the monsoon season. Situated at an elevation of approximately 2500 feet (762 meters) above sea level, Jog Falls is a significant tourist destination, drawing visitors with its raw power and scenic beauty. It&amp;rsquo;s conveniently located near popular destinations like Shimoga town (approximately 100 km away) and is a gateway to the Western Ghats, offering a blend of natural splendor and accessibility. The falls&amp;rsquo; unique formation, where the water doesn&amp;rsquo;t flow over a stepped rock face but plunges freely, makes it particularly captivating.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>