<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freedom Struggle on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/freedom-struggle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freedom Struggle on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/freedom-struggle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gandhi Jayanti</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/gandhi-jayanti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/gandhi-jayanti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-than-just-a-holiday-discovering-the-soul-of-gandhi-jayanti&#34;&gt;More Than Just a Holiday: Discovering the Soul of Gandhi Jayanti&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a day filled with quiet reflection, the gentle hum of spinning wheels, and the resonant echoes of prayer. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just another day off; it&amp;rsquo;s Gandhi Jayanti, a day deeply etched in the Indian psyche. For those unfamiliar with Indian culture, it might seem like just another national holiday. But trust me, it&amp;rsquo;s so much more. It&amp;rsquo;s a powerful reminder of the values that shaped a nation and continue to resonate across the globe – peace, truth, non-violence, and simple living.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parakram Diwas</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/parakram-diwas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/parakram-diwas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;honouring-the-braveheart-exploring-parakram-diwas-and-the-legacy-of-netaji-subhas-chandra-bose&#34;&gt;Honouring the Braveheart: Exploring Parakram Diwas and the Legacy of Netaji Subhas Chandra Bose&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a nation erupting in patriotic fervor, remembering a hero who dared to dream of a free India and dedicated his life to achieving it. That&amp;rsquo;s the essence of Parakram Diwas, celebrated annually on January 23rd to commemorate the birth anniversary of Netaji Subhas Chandra Bose, one of the most iconic and influential figures in India&amp;rsquo;s struggle for independence. More than just a birthday celebration, Parakram Diwas, meaning &amp;ldquo;Day of Valour,&amp;rdquo; is a tribute to Netaji&amp;rsquo;s unwavering courage, leadership, and relentless pursuit of freedom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
