<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Venkateshwara on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/venkateshwara/</link><description>Recent content in Venkateshwara on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:55:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/venkateshwara/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Balaji</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/balaji/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/balaji/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="balaji-an-encyclopedic-overview"&gt;Balaji: An Encyclopedic Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** Introduction**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Balaji, a popular epithet for Lord Venkateshwara, is one of the most widely revered forms of Vishnu within Hinduism. He is primarily worshipped in South India, particularly at the Tirumala Venkateswara Temple in Andhra Pradesh, which is one of the wealthiest and most visited religious sites in the world. Balaji embodies the preserving aspect of the Hindu trinity, representing compassion, justice, and the fulfillment of devotees&amp;rsquo; desires. His iconography is rich with symbolic meaning, and his worship plays a central role in the lives of millions of Hindus.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tirupati Thimmappa</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/tirupati-thimmappa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/tirupati-thimmappa/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tirupati-thimmappa-an-encyclopedic-overview"&gt;Tirupati Thimmappa: An Encyclopedic Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** Introduction**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tirupati Thimmappa, also known as Lord Venkateswara, is a highly revered deity in Hinduism, particularly in South India. He is considered a form of Lord Vishnu, the preserver in the Hindu trinity. Primarily worshipped at the Sri Venkateswara Temple in Tirumala, Tirupati, Andhra Pradesh, Thimmappa is renowned for his compassionate nature, wish-fulfilling abilities, and the massive scale of devotion he inspires. The deity is typically depicted standing in a majestic posture, adorned with elaborate jewelry and garments, representing divine sovereignty and prosperity. His significance in Hinduism lies in his accessibility to devotees and his promise of granting boons and liberation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>