<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Divine Feminine on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/divine-feminine/</link><description>Recent content in Divine Feminine on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:55:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/divine-feminine/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Devi</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/devi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/devi/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="devi-the-supreme-goddess-in-hinduism"&gt;Devi: The Supreme Goddess in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Devi, meaning &amp;ldquo;Goddess,&amp;rdquo; is the supreme deity in Hinduism, representing the feminine aspect of the divine. She is often understood as the ultimate power, the dynamic energy (Shakti) that underlies the universe. Devi is not merely a consort or a female counterpart to a male god; rather, she embodies the totality of existence and is considered the source of all creation, sustenance, and destruction.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Shakti</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/shakti/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/shakti/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="shakti-the-divine-feminine-creative-power-in-hinduism"&gt;Shakti: The Divine Feminine Creative Power in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shakti, often translated as “power” or “energy,” represents the primordial cosmic energy and the dynamic force that underlies the universe in Hinduism. She is the divine feminine creative power and is considered the active principle of all existence. While Brahman is often viewed as the static, unchanging, and unmanifested reality, Shakti is the dynamic, evolving, and manifested aspect of Brahman, bringing the universe into being. She is not simply a goddess but the very essence of divinity that empowers the male deities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>