<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Astrology on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/astrology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Astrology on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/astrology/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aswini</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/aswini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/aswini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;aswini-divine-physicians-and-the-first-nakshatra&#34;&gt;Aswini: Divine Physicians and the First Nakshatra&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Ashvins (also spelled Aswins), also known as the Ashwini Kumaras, are twin Hindu deities revered as divine physicians and healers. They are associated with health, rejuvenation, and dawn, often depicted as handsome youths riding golden chariots. Their association with the first nakshatra (lunar mansion) in Hindu astrology, Ashwini, which corresponds to the head of Aries, underscores their connection to new beginnings and auspiciousness. The Ashvins are prominent figures in Vedic literature and continue to be venerated, albeit to a lesser extent than more prominent deities like Vishnu or Shiva.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bharani</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/bharani/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/bharani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bharani-the-nakshatra-deity-of-transformation-and-endurance&#34;&gt;Bharani: The Nakshatra Deity of Transformation and Endurance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bharani, derived from the Sanskrit word meaning &amp;ldquo;bearing&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;carrying,&amp;rdquo; is the second Nakshatra, or lunar mansion, in Hindu astrology. This Nakshatra, spanning 13°20&amp;rsquo; to 26°40&amp;rsquo; Aries, is associated with themes of transformation, endurance, and the cycles of life and death. While Bharani isn&amp;rsquo;t typically personified as a deity in the same way as gods like Vishnu or Shiva, it is ruled by Yama, the god of death and dharma, and connected to the concept of Apabharani, representing the power to cleanse and purify. Its primary attribute revolves around the energy of beginnings and endings, often requiring individuals to face challenges with resilience and determination. Its significance lies in understanding the karmic burdens we carry and the transformative power that comes from confronting and overcoming them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
