<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Craftsman on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/craftsman/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Craftsman on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/craftsman/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tvashtri</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/tvashtri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/tvashtri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tvashtri-the-divine-craftsman-of-the-hindu-universe&#34;&gt;Tvashtri: The Divine Craftsman of the Hindu Universe&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tvashtri (Sanskrit: त्वष्टृ, romanized: &lt;em&gt;Tvaṣṭṛ&lt;/em&gt;), also known as Vishwakarma in later Hindu traditions, is a prominent deity in the Rigveda, revered as the divine craftsman, architect, and artisan. He is considered the creator of forms, the builder of the universe, and the maker of divine instruments and weapons. Tvashtri is associated with skill, ingenuity, and the creative power that shapes and sustains the cosmos. While not as widely worshipped as some other deities, Tvashtri’s role as the celestial artisan is essential to the Hindu cosmological framework. He is often depicted as a skilled artisan with tools, a measuring rod, or a chalice, symbolizing his craftsmanship and creative abilities. His significance lies in representing the inherent creative force in the universe and the transformative power of skilled artistry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vishwakarma</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vishwakarma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vishwakarma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vishwakarma-the-divine-architect-and-craftsman&#34;&gt;Vishwakarma: The Divine Architect and Craftsman&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vishwakarma, also known as the divine architect and craftsman, occupies a significant position in the Hindu pantheon. He is revered as the master of all crafts and the builder of the palaces of the gods. Depicted as a skilled artisan, he is often credited with creating the weapons, tools, and infrastructure used by both gods and demons. His association with creation, innovation, and craftsmanship makes him a particularly important deity for artisans, engineers, and architects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
