<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pragpur on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/categories/pragpur/</link><description>Recent content in Pragpur on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:57:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/categories/pragpur/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Experience Rich Culture and Natural Beauty at Pragpur Heritage Village</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/himachal-pradesh/experience-rich-culture-and-natural-beauty-at-pragpur-heritage-village/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/himachal-pradesh/experience-rich-culture-and-natural-beauty-at-pragpur-heritage-village/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pragpur Heritage Village, nestled in the Kangra district of Himachal Pradesh, India, is a living testament to a bygone era. Often referred to as &amp;ldquo;The Heritage Village,&amp;rdquo; Pragpur has remarkably preserved its colonial and traditional charm, making it a unique destination for history enthusiasts, culture seekers, and those looking for a tranquil escape. Located at an approximate elevation of 600 meters (1,969 feet) above sea level, Pragpur offers pleasant weather and breathtaking views of the surrounding landscape. It lies in proximity to other popular destinations in Himachal Pradesh, such as Dharamshala (approx. 65 km) and McLeod Ganj (approx. 70 km), making it an accessible addition to a broader Himalayan itinerary. The village&amp;rsquo;s unique blend of colonial architecture, traditional Himachali homes, and pristine natural beauty sets it apart, offering a glimpse into the past while providing a peaceful retreat from the hustle and bustle of modern life.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>