<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ayudha Puja</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/ayudha-puja/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/ayudha-puja/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;honoring-the-divine-in-the-everyday-a-celebration-of-ayudha-puja&#34;&gt;Honoring the Divine in the Everyday: A Celebration of Ayudha Puja&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever considered that the tools we use every day – from our laptops to our cars, from the chef&amp;rsquo;s knife to the artist&amp;rsquo;s brush – are not just inanimate objects but conduits of divine energy? In India, we have a beautiful tradition of acknowledging this sacred connection during Ayudha Puja, a vibrant festival that falls during the auspicious Navratri period. It&amp;rsquo;s a time when we pause, express gratitude, and seek blessings for the tools and instruments that empower our work and shape our lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vishvakarma Puja</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/vishvakarma-puja/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/vishvakarma-puja/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hammers-high-and-blessings-bound-celebrating-vishwakarma-puja-the-day-of-divine-craftsmanship&#34;&gt;Hammers High and Blessings Bound: Celebrating Vishwakarma Puja, the Day of Divine Craftsmanship&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have you ever stopped to think about the tools that build our world? The machines that power our industries? The hands that meticulously craft everything from our homes to our vehicles? In India, there&amp;rsquo;s a day dedicated solely to honoring these instruments and the divine force behind them: Vishwakarma Puja. It&amp;rsquo;s a celebration of craftsmanship, ingenuity, and the power of creation itself, all embodied in Lord Vishwakarma, the celestial architect and engineer of the gods.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
