<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Loyalty on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/loyalty/</link><description>Recent content in Loyalty on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:55:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/loyalty/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arundhati</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/arundhati/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/arundhati/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="arundhati-embodiment-of-virtue-and-constancy"&gt;Arundhati: Embodiment of Virtue and Constancy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** Introduction**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arundhati is a revered figure in Hinduism, primarily recognized as the wife of the esteemed sage Vashishta. She is not considered a goddess in the traditional sense, but rather a woman of exceptional virtue, devotion, and unwavering fidelity. She is intrinsically linked to the Saptarishi, the seven great sages, and is often identified with the morning star and the Alcor star, a faint companion star to Mizar in the constellation Ursa Major (the Big Dipper). Arundhati serves as an exemplar of marital devotion, chastity, and asceticism, making her a significant figure in Hindu traditions relating to marriage, family, and spiritual life. While not receiving widespread temple worship, her veneration lies in the symbolic representation of ideal womanhood and the invocation of her name in marriage rituals.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jatayu</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/jatayu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/jatayu/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="jatayu-the-noble-eagle-of-the-ramayana"&gt;Jatayu: The Noble Eagle of the Ramayana&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jatayu is a revered character in Hindu mythology, primarily known for his pivotal role in the epic Ramayana. This divine eagle is celebrated for his courage, righteousness, and selfless devotion to dharma, as evidenced by his valiant attempt to rescue Sita from the clutches of Ravana. Jatayu is not worshipped as a primary deity with dedicated temples in the same way as Vishnu or Shiva, but his story is deeply ingrained in Hindu culture as a powerful symbol of bravery and the unwavering commitment to moral principles. He is often depicted as a large, majestic eagle with human-like intelligence and compassion. His significance lies in his demonstration of dharma and his ultimate sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>