<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Katarmal on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/categories/katarmal/</link><description>Recent content in Katarmal on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:57:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/categories/katarmal/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Katarmal Sun Temple: A Glimpse into Ancient Solar Worship</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/uttarakhand/katarmal-sun-temple-a-glimpse-into-ancient-solar-worship/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/uttarakhand/katarmal-sun-temple-a-glimpse-into-ancient-solar-worship/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Katarmal Sun Temple, a resplendent architectural marvel dedicated to the Sun God, Surya, stands as a testament to ancient artistry and spiritual devotion. Nestled in the picturesque Almora district of Uttarakhand, India, this temple offers a captivating glimpse into the rich cultural heritage of the region. Located in the village of Katarmal, the temple is perched on a ridge, offering breathtaking panoramic views of the surrounding Kumaon Himalayas. Situated at an approximate elevation of 2,116 meters (6,942 ft), the temple provides a serene and spiritually uplifting experience, drawing both pilgrims and history enthusiasts. It&amp;rsquo;s relatively close to other popular destinations like Almora (approximately 20 km) and Kausani, making it a convenient addition to any Uttarakhand itinerary. What makes the Katarmal Sun Temple unique is its distinctive architectural style, the intricate carvings adorning its walls, and the historical significance associated with its creation, all coupled with its stunning location that enhances its aura.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>