<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maharashtra on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/maharashtra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Maharashtra on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/maharashtra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jyotiba</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/jyotiba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/jyotiba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;jyotiba-a-regional-light-deity-of-western-india&#34;&gt;Jyotiba: A Regional Light Deity of Western India&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jyotiba is a regional Hindu deity primarily venerated in the Western Indian states of Maharashtra and parts of Karnataka. He is considered a form of light, a symbol of divine radiance, and a protector of the common people, particularly the lower castes. Jyotiba&amp;rsquo;s worship is deeply rooted in folk traditions and local beliefs, contributing to the rich tapestry of Hindu religious practices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vithoba</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vithoba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vithoba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;vithoba-a-comprehensive-overview&#34;&gt;Vithoba: A Comprehensive Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vithoba, also known as Vitthal or Panduranga, is a Hindu deity predominantly worshipped in the Indian state of Maharashtra. Considered a manifestation of Krishna or Vishnu, he stands as a central figure in the Varkari tradition of Hinduism, a devotional movement emphasizing Bhakti (devotion) and egalitarianism. Vithoba is often depicted as a dark-complexioned youth standing arms akimbo on a brick, embodying compassion, accessibility, and a divine presence immanent within the devotee&amp;rsquo;s heart. His worship is deeply rooted in the cultural and spiritual landscape of Maharashtra, transcending caste and social barriers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
