<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spiritual on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/spiritual/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spiritual on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/spiritual/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brahman</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/brahman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/brahman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;brahman-the-ultimate-reality-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Brahman: The Ultimate Reality in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Hinduism, Brahman (ब्रह्मन्) represents the ultimate reality, the infinite, unchanging, eternal, and absolute principle underlying all existence. It is the supreme cosmic power and the source of everything that is, was, and ever will be. Brahman is not a deity in the traditional sense with a specific form or personality, but rather the unmanifested ground of being from which all gods and goddesses, the universe, and all beings emanate. Understanding Brahman is central to achieving &lt;em&gt;moksha&lt;/em&gt; (liberation) in many Hindu traditions. While not typically depicted with iconography like other deities, the symbol &amp;ldquo;Om&amp;rdquo; (ॐ) is often used to represent its essence. The significance of Brahman lies in its role as the foundation of reality and the goal of spiritual realization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diwali (Jainism)</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/diwali-jainism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/diwali-jainism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;beyond-the-lights-a-spiritual-awakening-with-jain-diwali&#34;&gt;Beyond the Lights: A Spiritual Awakening with Jain Diwali&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diwali, the Festival of Lights, is a name synonymous with dazzling displays of fireworks, the warm glow of diyas (oil lamps), and the sweetness of mithai (Indian sweets). But there&amp;rsquo;s a lesser-known, equally profound dimension to this festival, one that resonates with a quiet, inner radiance: Jain Diwali. While the rest of India celebrates the return of Lord Rama to Ayodhya, the Jain community marks this day as the nirvana kalyanak, the day Lord Mahavira, the 24th and last Tirthankara (spiritual teacher) of this era, attained moksha – liberation from the cycle of birth and death. For Jains, Diwali is a time for deep introspection, spiritual renewal, and a celebration of the victory of the soul over karmic bondage. It&amp;rsquo;s a day to dim the external lights and illuminate the inner self.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
