<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Langar on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/langar/</link><description>Recent content in Langar on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:55:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/langar/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Guru Nanak Jayanti</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/guru-nanak-jayanti/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/guru-nanak-jayanti/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="guru-nanak-jayanti-a-celebration-of-light-service-and-shared-humanity"&gt;Guru Nanak Jayanti: A Celebration of Light, Service, and Shared Humanity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a dawn breaking, not just with the rising sun, but with the rhythmic chanting of prayers, the aroma of freshly cooked langar wafting through the air, and the warm glow of community. This is Guru Nanak Jayanti, or Gurpurab, a celebration that transcends mere tradition. It’s a vibrant tapestry woven with threads of devotion, service, and the timeless teachings of Guru Nanak Dev Ji, the first Sikh Guru and the founder of Sikhism.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gurupurab</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/gurupurab/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/gurupurab/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="gurupurab-illuminating-the-world-with-love-and-service"&gt;Gurupurab: Illuminating the World with Love and Service&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever experienced a festival that feels like a warm embrace, a beacon of hope, and a celebration of selfless service, all rolled into one? Then you need to learn about Gurupurab, the Sikh festival commemorating the birth anniversaries of the Gurus, especially Guru Nanak Dev Ji, the founder of Sikhism. Growing up, Gurupurab was always a highlight of the year. The air filled with the melodic hymns, the aroma of freshly cooked langar wafted through the streets, and a sense of community and togetherness enveloped everything.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>