<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kali on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/kali/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kali on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/kali/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bhadrakali</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/bhadrakali/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/bhadrakali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bhadrakali-the-auspicious-fierce-goddess&#34;&gt;Bhadrakali: The Auspicious Fierce Goddess&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bhadrakali, a significant and revered deity in Hinduism, is a fierce yet auspicious form of Goddess Kali. She embodies both the destructive power to vanquish evil and the protective motherly aspect that bestows blessings and prosperity. Characterized by her dynamic iconography, Bhadrakali represents the powerful forces of creation and destruction, reminding devotees of the transient nature of existence and the ultimate triumph of good over evil. Her worship is prevalent across India, particularly in South India, and she holds a prominent position in Shaktism, the Hindu goddess tradition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mahakali</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/mahakali/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/mahakali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mahakali-the-supreme-goddess-of-time-and-transformation&#34;&gt;Mahakali: The Supreme Goddess of Time and Transformation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mahakali, often translated as &amp;ldquo;Great Kali&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Great Time,&amp;rdquo; is a Hindu goddess considered the supreme manifestation of Adi Shakti, the primordial cosmic energy, and a particularly powerful form of Kali. She embodies the destructive yet transformative aspects of time and is revered for her fierce protection and unwavering commitment to righteousness. While her iconography can be intimidating, Mahakali symbolizes the ultimate power of destruction necessary for renewal and spiritual liberation. She is primarily associated with Shaktism, the Hindu tradition that reveres the Divine Feminine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
