<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Swift on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/swift/</link><description>Recent content in Swift on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:55:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/swift/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Garuda</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/garuda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/garuda/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="garuda-the-eagle-mount-of-vishnu"&gt;Garuda: The Eagle Mount of Vishnu&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Garuda is a prominent deity in Hinduism, revered as the divine eagle mount (vahana) of the god Vishnu. He is primarily known for his immense strength, speed, and unwavering devotion to Vishnu, as well as his inherent enmity towards serpents (Nagas). Iconographically, Garuda is often depicted as a large, powerful bird-like creature, sometimes with human-like features, or as a fully human figure with avian characteristics like wings, beak, and claws. He is a symbol of courage, power, and protection against evil, and plays a significant role in Hindu mythology, cosmology, and religious practice. His image is frequently found adorning Vishnu temples, and he is considered an auspicious figure whose presence wards off negativity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Saranyu</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/saranyu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/saranyu/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="saranyu-the-cloud-goddess-and-divine-consort-of-surya"&gt;Saranyu: The Cloud Goddess and Divine Consort of Surya&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saranyu (Sanskrit: सरण्यू, IAST: &lt;em&gt;Saraṇyū&lt;/em&gt;), also known as Sanjna, is a prominent goddess in Hindu mythology. Primarily identified as the goddess of clouds, she is best known as the consort of Surya, the Sun God, and the mother of Yama (the god of death) and Yami (the goddess associated with rivers and twins). Her story, a tale of wifely duty, divine deception, and the origins of horses, features prominently in early Vedic literature. Saranyu is significant as a representation of feminine power, cosmic balance, and the complex relationship between mortals and the divine. Her role as the mother of Yama links her directly to concepts of mortality and judgment, key components of Hindu cosmology.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Vayu</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vayu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vayu/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vayu-the-hindu-god-of-wind"&gt;Vayu: The Hindu God of Wind&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vayu, also known as Pavana, is the Hindu deity of wind and air. He is a vital element in the Hindu cosmology, representing the breath of life and the force that permeates the universe. Vayu is not merely the atmospheric phenomenon but a powerful cosmic being responsible for the movement and vitality of all things. He is considered one of the five elements (Panchabhuta) – earth, water, fire, air, and space – that constitute the physical world. Vayu plays a significant role in the scriptures and is venerated for his strength, speed, and essential role in sustaining life. Iconographically, he is often depicted as a powerful figure, sometimes riding a deer or chariot, symbolizing his swiftness and control over the winds. His significance in Hinduism lies in his life-giving power, his role as a cosmic regulator, and his close associations with other prominent deities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>