<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>King on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/king/</link>
    <description>Recent content in King on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/king/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rama</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/rama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/rama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;rama-embodiment-of-dharma-and-ideal-king&#34;&gt;Rama: Embodiment of Dharma and Ideal King&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rama, also known as Ramachandra, is a major deity in Hinduism, revered as the seventh avatar of Vishnu. He is the central figure of the &lt;em&gt;Ramayana&lt;/em&gt;, one of the two great Indian epics. Rama is widely considered the embodiment of &lt;em&gt;dharma&lt;/em&gt; (righteousness, duty), ideal manhood, perfect fatherhood, and exemplary kingship. His consort, Sita, is revered as an embodiment of ideal womanhood and conjugal devotion. His significance in Hinduism is profound, influencing religious practices, art, literature, and societal values for millennia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yudhishthira</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/yudhishthira/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/yudhishthira/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;yudhishthira-the-embodiment-of-dharma&#34;&gt;Yudhishthira: The Embodiment of Dharma&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yudhishthira, also known as Dharmaraja (&amp;ldquo;King of Dharma&amp;rdquo;), is a central figure in the Hindu epic Mahabharata. He is the eldest of the five Pandava brothers and is renowned for his unwavering adherence to dharma (righteousness, duty, and moral order). Yudhishthira represents the ideal of a just and virtuous king, though his story is also marked by moral complexities and imperfections that serve as a profound exploration of dharma in action. His key attributes include honesty, integrity, a profound respect for truth, and a constant striving to uphold ethical principles, even in the face of immense adversity. While he doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a distinct iconography in the way some deities do, he is often depicted as a wise and dignified king, embodying serenity and moral authority. Yudhishthira&amp;rsquo;s significance lies in his representation of dharma and the challenges of living a righteous life, serving as a focal point for philosophical discussions about ethics, duty, and the consequences of one&amp;rsquo;s actions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
