<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Formless on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/formless/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Formless on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/formless/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brahman</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/brahman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/brahman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;brahman-the-ultimate-reality-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Brahman: The Ultimate Reality in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Hinduism, Brahman (ब्रह्मन्) represents the ultimate reality, the infinite, unchanging, eternal, and absolute principle underlying all existence. It is the supreme cosmic power and the source of everything that is, was, and ever will be. Brahman is not a deity in the traditional sense with a specific form or personality, but rather the unmanifested ground of being from which all gods and goddesses, the universe, and all beings emanate. Understanding Brahman is central to achieving &lt;em&gt;moksha&lt;/em&gt; (liberation) in many Hindu traditions. While not typically depicted with iconography like other deities, the symbol &amp;ldquo;Om&amp;rdquo; (ॐ) is often used to represent its essence. The significance of Brahman lies in its role as the foundation of reality and the goal of spiritual realization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parasiva</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/parasiva/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/parasiva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;parasiva-the-transcendent-shiva&#34;&gt;Parasiva: The Transcendent Shiva&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Parasiva represents the ultimate, transcendent aspect of Shiva in Hinduism. It is Shiva beyond all form, name, attribute, and limitation – the unmanifest Absolute, the source and essence of all creation. Unlike other depictions of Shiva, which are readily identifiable and anthropomorphic, Parasiva is formless and unmanifest, existing beyond the realm of human comprehension and sensory experience. It is the unchanging reality underpinning the manifest world and the goal of spiritual realization in Shaivism. The understanding of Parasiva is crucial to comprehending the entirety of Shiva&amp;rsquo;s nature, which includes both the transcendent and immanent aspects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
