<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Supreme on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/supreme/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Supreme on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/supreme/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Narayana</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/narayana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/narayana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;narayana-the-primordial-waters-and-source-of-creation-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Narayana: The Primordial Waters and Source of Creation in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Narayana is a significant deity in Hinduism, widely considered to be a form of Vishnu, one of the principal gods of the Hindu Trinity (Trimurti). He represents the cosmic waters, known as &lt;em&gt;Nara&lt;/em&gt;, and is revered as the source of all creation.  Depicted reclining on the serpent Shesha in the cosmic ocean, Narayana embodies tranquility, power, and the ultimate reality underlying the manifested universe. His iconography often includes representations of divine attributes such as the conch, discus, lotus, and mace, symbolizing his role as the sustainer and preserver of the cosmos.  Narayana holds paramount importance in Vaishnavism, where he is often considered the Supreme Being from whom all other deities emanate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parasiva</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/parasiva/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/parasiva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;parasiva-the-transcendent-shiva&#34;&gt;Parasiva: The Transcendent Shiva&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Parasiva represents the ultimate, transcendent aspect of Shiva in Hinduism. It is Shiva beyond all form, name, attribute, and limitation – the unmanifest Absolute, the source and essence of all creation. Unlike other depictions of Shiva, which are readily identifiable and anthropomorphic, Parasiva is formless and unmanifest, existing beyond the realm of human comprehension and sensory experience. It is the unchanging reality underpinning the manifest world and the goal of spiritual realization in Shaivism. The understanding of Parasiva is crucial to comprehending the entirety of Shiva&amp;rsquo;s nature, which includes both the transcendent and immanent aspects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
