<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dibrugarh on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/categories/dibrugarh/</link><description>Recent content in Dibrugarh on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:57:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/categories/dibrugarh/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dibru-Saikhowa National Park: A Haven for Nature Lovers</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/assam/dibru-saikhowa-national-park-a-haven-for-nature-lovers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/assam/dibru-saikhowa-national-park-a-haven-for-nature-lovers/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dibru-Saikhowa National Park, a biodiversity hotspot located in the Dibrugarh district of Assam, India, is a haven for nature enthusiasts and wildlife lovers. Situated at an elevation ranging from 118 to 125 meters above sea level, this park holds the distinction of being one of the 19 biodiversity hotspots in the world and forms a crucial part of the Eastern Himalayas. The park is strategically positioned, nestled between the Brahmaputra and Lohit rivers in the north and Dibru river in the south, offering a unique ecosystem and a picturesque landscape. It is located approximately 40 km from Dibrugarh town. The park&amp;rsquo;s unique charm lies in its diverse ecosystem, supporting a range of habitats from semi-evergreen forests to wet grasslands, making it a crucial habitat for numerous rare and endangered species. Its proximity to the Brahmaputra River ensures a vibrant aquatic life further enriching its biodiversity.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Explore the History of Tea at Assam Tea Estate</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/assam/explore-the-history-of-tea-at-assam-tea-estate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/assam/explore-the-history-of-tea-at-assam-tea-estate/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dibrugarh, often referred to as the &amp;ldquo;Tea City of India,&amp;rdquo; is a vibrant city located in the Dibrugarh district of Assam, India. Nestled in the northeastern part of the country, it sits on the banks of the Brahmaputra River, a lifeline for the region. The city is at an elevation of approximately 110 meters (360 feet) above sea level. Its strategic location provides easy access to popular destinations like Arunachal Pradesh and is a gateway to the eastern parts of Assam. Dibrugarh is renowned for its lush tea gardens, rich cultural heritage, and contributions to the Indian tea industry, making it a unique and captivating destination.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>