<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Barabar on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/categories/barabar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Barabar on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/categories/barabar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Barabar Hill Caves are the oldest surviving rock-cut caves in India</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/bihar/barabar-hill-caves-are-the-oldest-surviving-rock-cut-caves-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/places/bihar/barabar-hill-caves-are-the-oldest-surviving-rock-cut-caves-in-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Barabar Caves, situated in the Barabar hills near Gaya in the Indian state of Bihar, are a remarkable group of ancient rock-cut caves. They are a testament to the architectural and engineering prowess of ancient India.  These caves, believed to be among the oldest surviving rock-cut caves in the country, stand as silent witnesses to the religious and cultural shifts throughout history, primarily associated with Jainism and later, the Ajivika sect.  Lying approximately 24 kilometers (15 miles) north of Gaya and about 30 kilometers (19 miles) south of the city of Jehanabad, the Barabar Caves are readily accessible. Their unique polished surfaces, intricate carvings, and historical significance draw visitors from around the world. The caves themselves have an elevation varying depending on the specific cave, but the surrounding hills have an average elevation of approximately 300 meters (980 feet). The proximity to Gaya, a significant pilgrimage site for Hindus, makes a visit to the Barabar Caves an excellent addition to any itinerary exploring this part of Bihar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
