<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tiger on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/tiger/</link><description>Recent content in Tiger on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:55:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/tiger/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Waghoba</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/waghoba/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/waghoba/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="waghoba-the-tiger-god-of-maharashtras-tribal-communities"&gt;Waghoba: The Tiger God of Maharashtra&amp;rsquo;s Tribal Communities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waghoba, also known as Vyaghra Deva, is a tiger deity revered primarily by tribal communities in the Indian state of Maharashtra and surrounding regions. He is a significant figure in the local animistic traditions, representing the potent power of nature and the importance of respecting the delicate balance between humans and the environment. While not typically found within the mainstream Hindu pantheon with elaborate scriptures and established doctrines, Waghoba&amp;rsquo;s worship is deeply ingrained in the cultural fabric of these communities, reflecting their close relationship with the forests and the animals that inhabit them. His key attributes include strength, protection, and the embodiment of the wild. Iconographically, he is often represented by a simple stone or a rudimentary image depicting a tiger, embodying the essence of the majestic predator. Waghoba&amp;rsquo;s significance in Hinduism, particularly within the context of folk and tribal traditions, lies in his representation of the forces of nature that must be respected and appeased for the well-being of the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>