<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Modern on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/modern/</link><description>Recent content in Modern on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 20:55:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/modern/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jalaram</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/jalaram/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/jalaram/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="jalaram-a-19th-century-saint-deity-of-gujarat"&gt;Jalaram: A 19th-Century Saint-Deity of Gujarat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jalaram Bapa (1799-1881), a revered figure primarily worshipped in Gujarat, India, is a unique and relatively modern addition to the pantheon of Hindu deities. He is not mentioned in ancient scriptures like the Vedas or Puranas, distinguishing him from traditionally recognized gods and goddesses. Instead, Jalaram&amp;rsquo;s divinity stems from his extraordinary life of selfless service, particularly his unwavering commitment to feeding the hungry, irrespective of caste, creed, or religion. He is often depicted as a compassionate and humble figure, embodying the ideals of charity, devotion, and selfless action. His iconography typically includes a walking stick (Danda), a bowl for alms (Kamandalu), and often, a picture of his Guru, Bhoja Bhagat. Jalaram&amp;rsquo;s significance lies in his representation of the principles of Karma Yoga and the accessibility of divinity through virtuous living, offering a contemporary model for devotion and social responsibility within Hinduism.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Santoshi Mata</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/santoshi-mata/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/santoshi-mata/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="santoshi-mata-the-goddess-of-contentment"&gt;Santoshi Mata: The Goddess of Contentment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santoshi Mata is a relatively modern Hindu goddess revered as the embodiment of satisfaction, contentment, and happiness. Unlike many ancient Hindu deities, the worship of Santoshi Mata gained prominence primarily in the latter half of the 20th century, reflecting evolving spiritual needs and cultural shifts. Her key attribute is the ability to fulfill wishes and grant contentment to her devotees, particularly those who observe a strict fast (vrat) on Fridays. Iconographically, she is typically depicted as a beautiful, serene woman adorned in red clothing, holding a sword, a Trishul (trident), and a bowl of sweets. Her significance in Hinduism lies in her accessibility to everyday devotees and her association with domestic well-being, prosperity, and the alleviation of suffering.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Swaminarayan</title><link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/swaminarayan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/swaminarayan/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="swaminarayan-a-modern-deity-in-hinduism"&gt;Swaminarayan: A Modern Deity in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swaminarayan, also known as Sahajanand Swami, is a prominent figure in modern Hinduism, revered by his followers as a manifestation of God (Bhagwan). While not a deity featured in ancient Hindu scriptures, Swaminarayan occupies a significant position within the Swaminarayan Sampradaya, a Vaishnava Hindu denomination. He is recognized for his teachings on devotion, ethics, and social reform, particularly in the 19th century in Gujarat, India. His key attributes include compassion, wisdom, and spiritual authority. Iconographically, he is often depicted in saffron robes, holding a rosary and seated in a meditative posture. His significance lies in his establishment of a vibrant religious movement that emphasizes moral purity, selfless service, and the pursuit of spiritual enlightenment through bhakti (devotion).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>