<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Group Deity on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/group-deity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Group Deity on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/group-deity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vasu</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vasu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/vasu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-vasus-elemental-gods-of-cosmic-order&#34;&gt;The Vasus: Elemental Gods of Cosmic Order&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Vasus are a group of eight elemental deities in Hinduism associated with various aspects of the cosmos and nature. Their name, deriving from the Sanskrit root &amp;ldquo;vas,&amp;rdquo; meaning &amp;ldquo;to dwell&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;to shine,&amp;rdquo; reflects their essential role as custodians of the universe and the benevolent forces that sustain it. They represent fundamental aspects of the natural world and human existence, embodying principles of light, energy, and life. Although not always individually prominent, their collective presence signifies the interconnectedness of the cosmic elements and their influence on the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yogini</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/yogini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/yogini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;yogini-female-powers-and-tantric-practices-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Yogini: Female Powers and Tantric Practices in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Yoginis are a group of powerful female entities within Hinduism, often considered to be goddesses embodying supernatural abilities and associated with Tantric practices. They are viewed as both benevolent and potentially fierce, wielders of occult powers (siddhis), and integral to certain esoteric Hindu traditions, particularly Shaktism (the worship of the Divine Feminine). While not a single deity, the Yoginis are typically worshipped as a group, either as a collective of 64 or 81 entities, or in smaller groups. Their worship is central to Yogini temples, which are often circular in design, representing the cyclical nature of time and the cosmos. The Yoginis hold a significant place in the Tantric landscape, symbolizing the activation of inner energies and the attainment of spiritual liberation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
