<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Family on India</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/family/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Family on India</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bhai Dooj</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/bhai-dooj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/bhai-dooj/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bhai-dooj-a-celebration-of-sibling-love-that-shines-brighter-than-diwali&#34;&gt;Bhai Dooj: A Celebration of Sibling Love That Shines Brighter Than Diwali&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a festival bathed in the golden glow of autumn, filled with laughter, delicious aromas, and a tangible feeling of warmth. That’s Bhai Dooj, a beautiful Indian celebration that takes place right after Diwali, focusing on the cherished bond between brothers and sisters. While Diwali is the festival of lights, Bhai Dooj is the festival of sibling love, a day dedicated to strengthening ties and showering blessings upon each other. Forget presents and superficial gestures; Bhai Dooj is about genuine affection, protection, and a promise to always be there for each other, through thick and thin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eid al-Fitr</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/eid-al-fitr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/eid-al-fitr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;eid-mubarak-a-delicious-celebration-of-faith-family-and-forgiveness&#34;&gt;Eid Mubarak! A Delicious Celebration of Faith, Family, and Forgiveness&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine waking up to the aroma of freshly baked &lt;em&gt;sheer khurma&lt;/em&gt;, the soft glow of lanterns adorning homes, and the joyful chatter of loved ones. This is Eid al-Fitr in India, a vibrant festival that marks the end of Ramadan, the holy month of fasting. More than just a day of feasting, Eid is a time for reflection, renewal, and deep spiritual connection. It&amp;rsquo;s a celebration of patience, perseverance, and the strengthening of faith, culminating in an explosion of joy, gratitude, and community spirit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monti Fest</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/monti-fest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/monti-fest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;monti-fest-a-harvest-of-faith-family-and-flavors-in-mangalore&#34;&gt;Monti Fest: A Harvest of Faith, Family, and Flavors in Mangalore&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine the air thick with the scent of jasmine and fresh earth, the sounds of children&amp;rsquo;s laughter mingling with hymns, and tables laden with the bounty of the harvest. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just a dream; it&amp;rsquo;s the vibrant reality of Monti Fest, a cherished Mangalorean Catholic celebration that weaves together the Nativity of Mary and a joyous thanksgiving for the season&amp;rsquo;s first fruits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parents&#39; Worship Day</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/parents-worship-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/festivals/parents-worship-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;beyond-roses-celebrating-the-unconditional-love-of-parents-worship-day&#34;&gt;Beyond Roses: Celebrating the Unconditional Love of Parents&amp;rsquo; Worship Day&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day. The very words conjure images of red roses, heart-shaped chocolates, and candlelit dinners. But what if I told you there was an alternative, a day equally devoted to love, but one that celebrates the very foundation of our being: our parents? In India, a growing movement is embracing &amp;ldquo;Parents&amp;rsquo; Worship Day&amp;rdquo; on February 14th, not as a replacement for romantic love, but as a powerful complement – a dedicated day to honor the unwavering love, sacrifice, and guidance that our parents provide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
