<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Time on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</title>
    <link>https://india.muthu.co/tags/time/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Time on India Travel &amp; Culture Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 13:30:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://india.muthu.co/tags/time/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chandra</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/chandra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/chandra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chandra-the-lunar-deity-in-hinduism&#34;&gt;Chandra: The Lunar Deity in Hinduism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chandra, also known as Soma, is the Hindu god of the Moon. He is a significant celestial deity influencing the mind, emotions, and fertility. He is one of the Navagrahas (nine celestial bodies central to Hindu astrology) and is considered a benevolent god, associated with beauty, coolness, and tranquility. Chandra&amp;rsquo;s influence is felt in the cyclical changes of nature and is vital in determining auspicious timings for various activities according to Hindu tradition. His energy is believed to be calming and restorative, making him an important figure in both religious and astrological practices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kali</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/kali/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/kali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;kali-the-divine-embodiment-of-time-change-and-power&#34;&gt;Kali: The Divine Embodiment of Time, Change, and Power&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kali, often translated as &amp;ldquo;the black one&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;time,&amp;rdquo; is a prominent Hindu goddess associated with time, change, power, creation, preservation, and destruction. Revered as the fierce form of Durga, she represents the dynamic energy that both creates and dissolves existence. Kali is one of the ten Mahavidyas, fierce aspects of Adi Parashakti, the supreme goddess. While often perceived as terrifying, Kali is considered a loving mother figure to her devotees. Her iconography is striking, reflecting her role as the destroyer of ignorance and the embodiment of transformative power. Kali holds immense significance in Hinduism, particularly within Shaktism, where she is considered the ultimate reality or Brahman.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mahakali</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/mahakali/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/mahakali/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mahakali-the-supreme-goddess-of-time-and-transformation&#34;&gt;Mahakali: The Supreme Goddess of Time and Transformation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mahakali, often translated as &amp;ldquo;Great Kali&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Great Time,&amp;rdquo; is a Hindu goddess considered the supreme manifestation of Adi Shakti, the primordial cosmic energy, and a particularly powerful form of Kali. She embodies the destructive yet transformative aspects of time and is revered for her fierce protection and unwavering commitment to righteousness. While her iconography can be intimidating, Mahakali symbolizes the ultimate power of destruction necessary for renewal and spiritual liberation. She is primarily associated with Shaktism, the Hindu tradition that reveres the Divine Feminine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shani</title>
      <link>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/shani/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://india.muthu.co/posts/gods/shani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;shani-the-lord-of-karma-and-justice&#34;&gt;Shani: The Lord of Karma and Justice&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shani, also known as Śanaiścara, is a prominent Hindu deity associated with the planet Saturn (Śani). Revered as the dispenser of justice and the lord of karma, Shani&amp;rsquo;s influence on an individual&amp;rsquo;s life is considered profound. He is neither inherently benevolent nor malevolent, but rather a force of cosmic balance, rewarding righteous actions and punishing wrongdoing. His key attributes include a slow pace (Śanaiścara literally means &amp;ldquo;slow-moving&amp;rdquo;), discipline, austerity, and profound wisdom born of experience. Iconographically, Shani is often depicted as dark in complexion, adorned with black clothing, and riding a crow or buffalo. In Hinduism, Shani holds significant importance as a judge of moral behavior and a facilitator of spiritual growth through karmic retribution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
